Sunny: Hey, hello, everyone. I'm audible to all of you. Can you please confirm in the chat if you can hear me?
Sunny: Good evening, guys. Let's begin with this class. Let's begin with the session.
Sunny: I hope I am, audible and visible to all of you, right guys?
Sunny: Okay, great.
Sunny: So, today guys, we are having a discussion around the… Assignment, okay?
Sunny: So, just a second, guys, let me open the submission of the assignment.
Sunny: Yeah, you can start from the rack.
Sunny: You can definitely start from there.
Sunny: So guys, let's do one thing, let's start, basically, the discussion around the assignment.
Sunny: And when I gone through the submission of the assignment, so in total, I found around 60 plus solution. So this is all the solution of the assignment. Let me show you the actual sheet.
Sunny: So, did you submit your assignment?
Sunny: Guys, did you submit your assignment, yes or no?
Sunny: So this is the actual sheet, where basically I'm getting the submission of the assignment.
Sunny: I hope it is visible to all of you. Now, if you will see the assignment number 4,
Sunny: So, there, basically, you will find out around, 60 to 70 entries related to the assignment 4, okay?
Sunny: So this assignment, basically, it was around the fine-tuning, okay?
Sunny: Now, I think, many of you, you have done a very good job. I gone through with those, solutions. See, here is all the solution, basically, where I gone through, the different, different solution from the different, different people.
Sunny: And I think everyone is, not available over here to represent their assignment, but yeah, whoever is available, they can represent their assignment, okay? So this is what, guys, this is the solution of the different, different people.
Sunny: Now guys, let's do one thing. Let's, give the chance to the, basically, this assignment, solver, right? So they can demonstrate the solution in front of everyone.
Sunny: And, then, basically at the end, we'll have a, final conclusion, okay? So, which one is the best one? Which solution is the best one? Something like that, something like that, guys, we can, decide at the end of this session.
Sunny: So I will create one poll where I'll keep the name of all the demonstrators, right? And then, basically, we'll only provide the vote of those people, and then, on behalf of that only, we are going to decide who's going to win this entire challenge, okay? I think you already know the prize of this challenge, so whoever is going to win this challenge, right, the top 3% will get access to the advanced badge.
Sunny: So, we are going to launch one more batch, I think within a week itself, right? So, next week, we have a launch of that batch. So, definitely, we'll get access of that particular batch. Now, let's do one thing, guys. First of all, see, this is all the solution.
Sunny: Tell me how many of you are there. Can you please raise the hand if you are ready for the demonstration? If you are willing for the demonstration, just let me know in the chat so that I can proceed with your name. Okay. Now there are some rule, right? So some rule basically I'll define before going into the demonstration.
Sunny: Otherwise, it will be the endless conversation. So, I think there is around 50 to 20 people, okay? So, each person will get around 5 to 10 minutes, and how they have to represent their assignment, even I will talk about that, okay?
Sunny: So, guys, you can see the names Sunil, Ravi, Sachin, Piyush, okay, Vansh, Kati, Promita, Lokesh, Deepesh, Ranjan. So, there is around 50 to 60 names, or even more than that. I can see everyone is not available, okay?
Sunny: But yeah, whoever is available, you can raise the hand if you have submitted the assignment. Definitely I'll check out the entry over here while you are going to represent your solution.
Sunny: And then only you can proceed. Okay? Now, guys, one more thing. See?
Sunny: So, assignment is there, you submitted that, and going forward, again, you are going to be getting many assignments, so many different, different assignments, okay? So, what I'm thinking, I will create a new Google Form, so that you can freshly submit, or basically the same Google Form, I will take a submission of the assignment, those assignments, okay?
Sunny: Now, along with the assignment, basically, I will provide the solution as well.
Sunny: So, after this discussion, you will find out the solution over the GitHub itself. So, directly, you can download the solution from there, and you can do the practice, okay? If you haven't submitted your solution.
Sunny: Now guys, let's, let me define the, the process of the demonstration. So, first, what you have to do, let's say, let's suppose this is your project, okay? So, here is a person, Sunil. So, Sunil has submitted their solution. Okay, let me open this particular solution.
Sunny: And guys, I have seen, like, many of you, you are not posting it over the LinkedIn. Why you are not posting, guys?
Sunny: Oh?
Sunny: Is it a bad assignment, or, you don't want to be, like, public your work, or you don't want to be posting? Post, guys. See, there are hundreds of posts which is being posted, like, around to this kind of stuff and all. Now, your solution will be stand out among all those, different stuff in the solution, okay?
Sunny: So this is, like, very good assignment. Here, you have learned so many things. So just post it.
Sunny: Okay? Just post it. See, we are not saying that you have to promote to anyone. Just promote yourself.
Sunny: Right? Again, I'm saying, just promote yourself. I'm not saying you have to promote to me, or to anyone, or to Krishna, or to Krishna Academy. See, it's a secondary thing.
Sunny: But the first is the… first person is you, okay? So I would definitely recommend you to post this solution over the LinkedIn, okay? Keep it over the GitHub, just organize each and everything in a very structured manner. So whenever you are going in an interview, whenever, basically.
Sunny: it is required to you, you can take a help of this particular solution, right? Now, guys, how, basically, you are going to be represented assignments, if this is the, like, solution which is built by the Sunil, right?
Sunny: Now, first of all, basically, you need to talk about the problem statement, what problem statement you have solved, okay? Now, after defining that, after defining the problem statement and all, from where you took the data, what kind of data you are using for the fine-tuning.
Sunny: Right? Then, basically, you have to give the code a demonstration, okay? Like this, this, this, I have done that, okay?
Sunny: And guys, before that, before explaining the problem statement, before basically, before explaining the problem statement, before going through the data, before going through the, the code base and all, you need to showcase the final result, right? So just execute the code, first showcase the final result.
Sunny: Now, how your application is working, what answer it is generating, okay? What, just write the question, generate the answer, and then only start your demonstration. So, for each demonstration, I will give 8 to 10 minutes, okay? Max to max 10 minutes, right?
Sunny: So, because there are so many people, if, let's say 15 people are giving the demonstration, and if I'm going to be multiply with the 10, right, so it is around 150 minutes.
Sunny: Okay, so 150 minutes, even I can bear up to 180 minutes, or even more than, basically, 2 to 3 hours, okay? So around, like, till 11, basically, we can… till 11 or 12, basically, we can take this, all the demonstration and all, okay?
Sunny: So, we can be at around 200 to 240 minutes, that is also fine. Till 12, basically we can, go through with this, all the demonstration and all, okay? So, to each person, I will provide 10 minutes, so you just have to, like, give the demonstration in the same way, which I told.
Sunny: Okay, so first showcase the result, then define the problem statement, then talk about the, basically, data upside, okay, and then, basically, discuss the codebase and all, right? So in this particular format, you have to go, okay?
Sunny: So, I hope, guys, everything is clear. So, are you ready? Please let me know in the chat if you are ready then, so that I can allow to some participant.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Okay, great, guys.
Sunny: So, let's start, let me check whoever is there, then I'll allow to you.
Sunny: So let me stop sharing my screen, and then, guys, I'll add you as a panelist, you can share your screen, okay?
Sunny: So I'm stop sharing my screen, just a second.
Sunny: Okay, now, Yash, if you are there, Yash Shukla, Bhargav, Sumit, guys, would you like to go with the assignment solution?
Yash Shukla: Yes, sir, on my audible.
Sunny: Just a second.
Sunny: Yeah, yes, please, tell me now. Sorry, please speak something now. Can you hear me?
Yash Shukla: Am I… am I audible to you now?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you are audible. So, would you like to go first.
Yash Shukla: Yes, sir.
Sunny: Okay, so I'm adding in a panelist, you can go with yours,
Sunny: Solution, okay? Demonstration. Now, after that, Bhargav, you can go, then Sumit, you can represent, okay?
Sunny: Sure. And guys, if you have any sort of a question, then please write it down in the chat. So, even I will be there in the backend. You can, write any sort of a question in the chat. I will try to reply your questions.
Sunny: Got it? And even, we can have some doubt or discussion as well after each demonstration, okay? So the, demonstrator also can pick those questions, and it can answer related to that specific solution, okay? So in this, in that way, actually.
Sunny: we are, we are moving. Got it? So, yeah, Yash, you can share the screen, and then, start, with the result first, then, explain the problem statement, data set, and then showcase the code base, okay?
Yash Shukla: Please go ahead.
Sunny: Yeah. Guys, and feel free to open your camera as well, there is no such restriction. If you want to showcase your face, show your face, okay? There is no such restriction like that. Open your camera, okay, and switch on your camera, and then show your face, in whatever way you wanted to go, go, okay? Yeah.
Yash Shukla: Sure, sir, my camera is, you know, just, you know, not working, so…
Sunny: Fine, it's up to you, yes, no worry, okay? It's not a mandatory one.
Yash Shukla: Sir, yes, is my screen visual, do you?
Sunny: Yeah, it is visible.
Yash Shukla: So, so you can see in my, you know, GitHub repo that there are so many files, the front-end, fine-tuning, back-end ones. So the project which you gave, I implemented it, and I went deep dive into it, and my thought process was to
Yash Shukla: just not only ask the question, but to bring a front-end and back-end tool. So, currently, I was not able to do such thing, but I was able to do the project only, just fine-tuning part. So, if I have to show you my, first, the result, then, I'll show you this.
Yash Shukla: If you can see… see, you have asked me to also compare the result and the output of every, model and every adapter. So if you can see this screen, I was using the Qwen 2.5 1.5 billion insect model.
Yash Shukla: So, there were two adapters which I used. One was the flow, you know, the SFT and the DPU one, which I've trained. So, you asked us to take around 50 paragraphs for, fine, tuning, SFT, and 10 paragraphs, I think, for DPU.
Yash Shukla: So, my dataset was originally carrying 26,000 value samples. So, I took 600 for SFT, and I took 150 for DPO.
Yash Shukla: for a free collab on this. So, if you can see the answer…
Sunny: So yes, this is working. If it is working, can you showcase the result, instead of just read me?
Yash Shukla: Sir, the result I've stored in this README file only, the compar.
Sunny: That I got. Later on, you can come over here, but as of now, can you run it at least once? Because you created a front-end, back-end… Okay, so I wanted to show you front-end, like, how did you create, okay, what parameter you're passing from the front-end, so please run it.
Yash Shukla: Sir, in my… I can run this project, but sir, in my front-end, I'm not able to just connect this thing. My front-end and back-end both are running, but I'm not able to just attach this, because if you remember, you told me about the inference API, inference playground. So I was currently studying for that thing.
Yash Shukla: My front end…
Sunny: Okay, okay, okay, no worries.
Yash Shukla: Okay.
Sunny: The one.
Yash Shukla: No problem.
Sunny: Yeah, whatever is working, please, go ahead.
Yash Shukla: Okay, sure, sure, sure. So…
Sunny: Please keep the time constant in your mind, okay? So, 10 to 12 minutes, within that, try to finish. Got it?
Yash Shukla: Okay, sir. So, first, I have to tell my output. There were four things which I, executed, like blue, rock, which I learned from the assignment. If I can tell one more line about everything to you and to everyone, if it is okay?
Yash Shukla: Sir, can I,
Sunny: Sorry, can you please come again?
Yash Shukla: If I can, tell one, one, just line up for every, this thing, why I chose this…
Sunny: You can talk about that, no worries, okay?
Yash Shukla: Sir, like, if we have to see the coin-based model, answer, and the total words and character and sentences, everything, every, all of this parameter.
Yash Shukla: So, the blue ROG1, ROG2, and ROGL, they were something like, they were taking some subset of string or some subset of words, and they were comparing with each and every answer given by adapter, given by base model, or given by DPU.
Yash Shukla: So, when ROG1 was something like, we were getting one word exactly matching from the…
Yash Shukla: Output of the prompt. Then, we were getting this code.
Yash Shukla: And the bird score was something like an F1 score we know in machine learning models, so this is the calculated F1 score, which is as a bird score. So for every prompt, as 10 prompts were given, we have, 10 standard prompts, so I've calculated everything for each prompt, like, for when
Yash Shukla: base model, I was getting the words, the characters, the sentence, and the… Output.
Yash Shukla: And if you can see for SFT local, which I've stored in my local system, I was getting this number of parameters. If I can compare this, the BERT score for coming for this one, it was 0.83. For SFT, it was coming 0.84. And for DPU, it was coming for this.
Yash Shukla: So, if I have to say, the accuracy was improved in most of the prompts. In few prompts, it was static. So, these are all the things which I learned, and also, sir, if I have to show you my, this file.
Yash Shukla: the…
Yash Shukla: collab file, which I had worked on, so there were these commands. Like, I've made one SRC folder in which comparison folder, and inside one, I've just ran the command. So…
Yash Shukla: These were 10 standard prompts which were being evaluated for every adapter, like for base model. If you can see, then it was going for the SFT local model, and then it was coming for the DPU model.
Yash Shukla: And… Sir, this was my project structure that I…
Yash Shukla: ran the clone command in full, then I installed the dependencies inside my system, and again, if I have to show two important things. Like, I also, got to know that how we can upload and download files from this unzip command
Yash Shukla: and many other things, and see, I've also just pasted the results here, like loading, comparison, configuration.
Yash Shukla: And, if I have to just run the front-end backend, if I can show you right now… So…
Yash Shukla: I will… Yes, the OmniAssist files.
Yash Shukla: So, let's go through with what that means.
Yash Shukla: It's taking some work, it should not…
Yash Shukla: And, yes, sir. And, it is… it will run by its own, because my environment has started.
Yash Shukla: If I have to show you all my other files, then… I've fooled…
Yash Shukla: So, sir, this, again, I have to, so, I was, sir, just comparing, every model, and one important thing which I did, you asked about the…
Yash Shukla: comparison. So, I created a sample file, a sample file in the sense, if we are having more than one adapter, more than two adapter, or any number of models, then we can also compare it, and I can show you this, it was created very, you know, beautifully, so if I have to show you, close in this…
Yash Shukla: Src, and then, yes, comparison. And it was in the compare models.
Sunny: What I would suggest, you keep everything in structure, right? First of all, as I told you, talk about the problem statement, okay, what kind of… Because, if you remember, I've given this assignment for the multiple domain-specific data, right?
Yash Shukla: That's so.
Sunny: So you can choose any sort of a domain, and on top of that, you can build your problem. So we should always talk about the problem statement if we are going to be explaining our project to anyone.
Sunny: Okay. Right? So, going that way, if you're not.
Yash Shukla: That's a jo.
Sunny: Don't worry, you can join after that, because only 4 minutes is left for you, so later on also you can represent that, we can give chance to any other person, okay?
Yash Shukla: Sure, sir, so, you know, thank you for… so I can just continue next time, or, after…
Yash Shukla: You know, somebody else?
Sunny: Yeah, definitely you can.
Yash Shukla: Sure, sure, sure, sure.
Sunny: Okay, next, let me call out the names. So, Bhargav, Bala, Mandeep, anyone is there, guys? You can go.
bala personal: Yeah. Hi, Sunny. Yeah.
Sunny: Bala…
bala personal: Can I go S.
Sunny: You know, penalties Mandeep, are you ready? Jyoti, Mand.
Mandeep Motan: So, we'll.
Jyoti Gupta: What are your.
sumit das: Perfect.
Sunny: Yeah. Okay.
sumit das: Dam.
Sunny: If I'm also adding in a panelist, then Jyoti is also there, okay?
bala personal: Thank you.
Sunny: I'm adding you also.
Sunny: Okay.
Mandeep Motan: want to order them.
Sunny: Yeah, guys, go ahead. So…
bala personal: Can I, can I.
Sunny: Bala, you can go ahead, yeah.
bala personal: Okay. Thank you, sir. Thank you for giving me an opportunity to share the project, what I have done.
bala personal: Yeah, I will take only 5 to 10 minutes, yeah. So, this, so this is set up, sir. So, the product statement, what I had done, you know, HR Policy Assistant, I can see a README file. So,
bala personal: yeah, I built a HR policy assistant, which can answer HR questions related to, you know, employee, like, employee, remote, remote work, and, you know, what are the policies in HR, like, and, absence policies, you know, kind of, you know,
bala personal: all… all kind of, you know, whatever you want to get a HR-related question and answers, you're going to get it, actually.
bala personal: So, there are… for this, I have made use of, three stages. One is non-instruction, instruction, and preference, actually. So, for each and every, non-instruction data set, I prepared a 304 raw data. It's a paragraph. It's a raw data. And, 504 JSON5 HR,
bala personal: Question and answer space, and 203 depot examples I prepared. It's available in the dataset folder, okay?
bala personal: So this is a complete raw text, that I prepared. It can answer about your completely, HR-related information, like, I'm eligible for the, you know, remote work or not, you know, how many hours of,
bala personal: how many hours of vacation we can take, you know, how many, you know, leaves, sick leaves is present, and, you know,
bala personal: So, are you…
Sunny: Are you sharing your screen? Sorry, I cannot see the data, Bala. I think you're just sharing a single screen. Share the entire screen, okay?
bala personal: Yeah, yeah, sure, sure, sure. I'm sorry, I'm
bala personal: Yeah, I'm sorry. So, I was telling about the, you know, dataset, sir. I prepared it, if you see the data folder.
bala personal: There are three data sets available. One is instruction, one is non-instruction, and one is preference data set. So let me talk about non-instruction data set. You see a very big raw text file.
bala personal: which contains complete information about your, HR policies, and, you know.
bala personal: Completely about your remote work information, absences, you know, sick leaves, are you eligible for your remote work or not, kind of notice period, how many, you know, how much notice period you want to serve in this company.
bala personal: So all these, you know, eligible, data is present, I prepared, it's around 607 lines of data, it's company raw text.
bala personal: And for instruction data set, you know, I prepared around, you know.
bala personal: six, let me say, it's around 501 instructions, because to train the efficient LLM, we need a huge data set to understand the complete business process, so I prepared a very huge, data set to, you know.
bala personal: to get efficient model out of that. So, next preference data set, I just have, you know,
bala personal: I have only about 200, it's around, one second, sir, two, 300, 300 data sets. First, initially, I, initially, I prepared only 200, but, you know, I'm getting some kind of, you know.
bala personal: hallucinating responses. So I prepared more 100 JSONs. Now it's very good actually. I can, it's very accurate. I'm getting accurate results.
bala personal: And next, I, actually, I'm not able to prepare a front-end. I just prepared a Streamlit app to do this. I'll go into that, but I did not… I don't have any GPU, so I did not go into that. So, I'll go into the inference, and I know how the note
bala personal: So first, let me go to non-instruction Colab. This is not trained file, and this is one I trained on the Colab, actually.
bala personal: what I… I have taken three-step process. One is on raw text, next to instruction, and preference, right? So, I'm going to non-instruction. In the non-instruction, what I have done, I prepared a, I… I taken the Qwen… Qwen-based model, non-instruction, Qwen-based model, and the top of that, I…
bala personal: you know, I prepared the raw data, and I uploaded to the Hugging Face, because I don't have a GP in my system.
bala personal: So that was the reason I uploaded the base model instruction fine-tuning model. Like you can see, right, LoRa base model with LoRa. You see the responses trained with the SFT trainer. Like, what exactly you teach, no, sir? Like, I've taken your references.
bala personal: Exactly, I put the same, thing, but I put some kind of epoch, more… I increase some of, you know, some of the parameters.
bala personal: I just, you know, learned and, you know, done that, actually. So, some completely have taken your, class notes, and, I now copy-paste the same thing, actually. You see, right? What is the step and training loss? It is starting from 20 to 100. How the training loss is getting… it's getting decreased
bala personal: to 1.06, means 2.72, it's been decreasing, decreasing to 1.06, means we are good with the base model. And next, what I would answer, I upload it to the… I just save the model, and I upload it to the hugging face, actually.
bala personal: So, it is… now, it… the, the model, the base model is present in the hugging phase. Upload to my repository. You see here, at the IC, hugging phase integration I have done. And, with a username, password, this is my, this is my repo name, HR Policy Assist
bala personal: And, this is my username.
bala personal: I uploaded to the Hugging Face. Now what I have done in the instruction fine tuning, I integrated Hugging Face. I downloaded the non-instruction base model into this instruction fine tuning you see here.
bala personal: So first, I, you know, these are all, pip install and everything, transformer, import GPU check, configuration, so this is where it is. I'm, I'm loading the model from the hugging face. So, first stage is.
bala personal: Uploaded there, now I'm downloading from the Hugging Face, actually, with the direct integration of, username, password with the HF token, actually. You see here, HF token.
bala personal: And next, here, these are configuration, lower rank, and, projection, target models, and everything, right? So, whatever you teach, sir, I've just put whatever here, actually. Nothing, I did not extra go into that, but I just, added more on the configuration side of that house.
bala personal: And loading data set that for what I have done here, instruction data set I'm loading and I'm fine tuning the base model now with the instruction data set.
bala personal: And at the end, again, I'm applying LoRa and training the model with the get from pre-trained, whatever he taught me. So the same applied here.
bala personal: And SFT… SFT config, the same, you see your configuration same, but I have used the FP16, BF16, kind of, you know, and this is the one, Adam 8-bit. I think you use 16-bit somewhere. But I… I… I just R&D, and I will… I put, like, which is the best one to…
bala personal: get accuracy out of that model, actually. So, you see, I have done 180 step process. Out of 180, I got 1.06 at the end. It means
bala personal: the model getting accuracy from step by step, 20, 40, 60, to 180, 180 you see here also, batch size, and number of examples, again, number of boxes, 3.
bala personal: number of steps is 189 I put, so it's put up to 180, so I got a good results here. And now, again, save the model, fine-tuned model, again uploaded to the Hugging Face, actually.
bala personal: Again, I'm uploading to the hugging face of, with the stage 2, actually, if you see here. HR policy has a stage 2. So, again, in the next process, DPO, alignment, DPO alignment collab training.
bala personal: I downloaded the same Ginkface model at the top. Let me go into that.
bala personal: So the same, I'm downloading stage two. And again, stage two and applying the dataset. With the same, I'm using FP16 seed 42 and gradient descent eight seed 42. So 42 reproducibility.
bala personal: And I'll load preference data set with the preference data. This is the one data set, JSNL file.
bala personal: And, apply LoRa trained with the DPO.
bala personal: Yeah.
bala personal: After getting the, you see, a DPO config. In the DPO config with, with the 8-bit, auto-optim, auto-mate 8-bit, actually, and output at a stage, DPO3.
bala personal: Yeah, number of learning rate. Learning rate, I just increases. If you see learning rate, what are the learning rate here? Yeah, I present in the configuration, actually, here. So learning rate, a warm-up, yeah, learning rate is
bala personal: 1u4, actually.
bala personal: So, so it's, more, more lending efficient. And here, number of steps is, you see here, number of total steps is 114. So, you see training loss, reward chosen, everything I'm getting printed, actually. What is the rejected, what are the rewards, what are the,
bala personal: Adam got, actually. So, it's it's most efficient now, 0.0095, means it's going to
bala personal: whatever question asked, it's going to give accuracy. Accuracy
bala personal: is the top priority, so now. So… and again, I save the model.
bala personal: And, I uploaded to the Hugging Face, actually, with the HR policy session, final. Okay? Now, you see, if you see my report, all the stages of… all the stages model will be present now. So, what I have done next? Inferencing. So, now, everything, I have to do… I have to do inferencing with the
bala personal: last model, because this one is the most, most efficient model. Now, I got the most efficient model out of three models with the DPO, right? So, human preference,
bala personal: answers we are going to get it, actually. So inference, in the inference.colab file,
bala personal: I had an inferencing now. So, what I had done, I had, again, I downloaded the, you know, whatever, I loaded the HF, you see here, I loaded the HF with the final model, load the model, and generate answer. So, what I'm asked here,
bala personal: So, whatever you taught me, sir, like, what… the syntax, everything I put is the same. I did not use any difference. So, I'm star… I'm star system. I'm your helpful HR… HR policy assistant. Answer the HR-related question in the company policies. So, this is the question I ask you, sir, saying that…
bala personal: Yeah.
bala personal: I'm going to down… yeah, the question, how many casual leaves can I take per year with a 200 length of your token, token text? I mean, to say, like, we can, we can…
bala personal: We can limit the response of the model 200 and 0.5 temperature actually.
bala personal: So, I got the response again. Company does not have specific limit of casual pay per year, assistant user even, but policy encourages to employ the efficient avoid to work. Next question I had asked, what is the notice period in the… what is the notice period for the resignation?
bala personal: It gives me a very good answer, saying that the notice period for the resignation is 60 days per the employee at manager level and above.
bala personal: It means that whatever I trained, in the dataset, I'm getting exactly the word. So it means there is no, I mean.
bala personal: I did not see any hallucinating, you know, out of, context response, actually.
Sunny: Okay. That's… that's great. So, Bala, you have done a great job. I can see a lot of effort over there.
Sunny: That's very good. Now, see, one more thing. See, you created a StreamlitApp.py.
Sunny: Yes, sir. So, is it working? Have you connected with your backend code, backend application, this one?
bala personal: No, sir, actually, what I have done, right? I'm directly connecting with the, this I'm trying to upload to, actually, I was tried in Colab, it's not working, I was not able to open the port,
Sunny: You have created this inference.py. You can directly connect it with the stream.py for the inferencing and all, right? You can load the model from the Hugging Face API directly.
Sunny: So that kind of enhancement also you can do, but yeah, you did a good, work. Now, can you showcase the result, basically, the readme.py file, which I asked you to create for the evaluation and all, just to make a comparison in between? So have you created that kind of comparison also?
bala personal: Yes, sir, sir. SFT model comparison.
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: Just talk about that, and, you have done a good job, so yeah, it's, like, great work.
Sunny: Voila.
bala personal: So whatever you teach me, sir, every time I'm done, same things, I like it, not too extra.
bala personal: I'm just realizing, yeah, with this project So…
bala personal: Yeah, this is a comparison, what is the improvement I got it, these waters. I just put everything reports here.
bala personal: And how to install, is readme file. So in readme file, whatever I done, put a how many data set, instruction, how to do this, what is the base model I use, lower rank, I just put on evaluation results, you know.
bala personal: 3 by 10, completeness 4 by 10, actionability is overall, I got 4.0 by 10. DPO, I got 9.4, actually.
bala personal: Chrissy.
bala personal: This is the implement, I got it.
Sunny: So in the DPO, basically you got a more accurate, more accurate result, correct? And I can see the result also. So how did you generate this metrics? Did you take a help of the copilots over here?
bala personal: Yeah, yeah, normal, the normal, what I've intelligent, I said, like, I go, I, I, I got the, like, whatever Colab results I got, I given to, Copilot saying that, can you please evaluate and give me the response, give me the, you know, correct results.
Sunny: That's.
bala personal: So…
bala personal: evaluated, normal, like, here, in our Intel, sorry, in our, VS Code, so it's given me this file, sir, evaluation results.
Sunny: Okay, okay, that's great, that's great. Yeah, you can, I think, walk through the entire readme. So, yeah, you have mentioned Onslaught, Laura, and all everything. Yeah, that's great, Bala. So, yeah, good job, Bala. So, guys, how was the solution? I think you also liked that.
Sunny: So, anyone would like to appreciate Tuvala, you can, mention in the chat, guys, and even, see, you can, ask the question, in the chat itself, okay? So, even I will try to answer for those questions.
Sunny: And the person who is demonstrating their solution, they can also take your questions, okay? You can write in the chat itself.
bala personal: Cheers.
Sunny: Great, Bala, thank you.
Sunny: So, fine, guys, now let's go for the next solution, and if you have any sort of a doubt, just write it down in the chat, we'll take care of that doubt. And Bala, please look into the chat, if you are, able to answer for those questions, please answer, okay?
bala personal: Sure, sir. 100%, sir.
Sunny: So, thank you, Bala. Now, Bala, I think you took 4 minutes more. That's fine, but the solution was great. The next person who can go next, Jyoti, please go.
Jyoti Gupta: Yeah, hi everyone. So let me present my screen, screen.
Jyoti Gupta: Please let me know if you're able to see my screen.
Jyoti Gupta: Oh.
Jyoti Gupta: So, hi everyone. Here, my problem statement is, like, I have created a front-end also for this.
Jyoti Gupta: So, basically, if I go here…
Jyoti Gupta: I've created a short PPT, so that everyone can… it can be understandable to everyone. Basically, what my business problem is, like, as a corporate employee, we usually waste hours, like, on our routine IT questions.
Jyoti Gupta: So if we go with the generic LLM, it will give us generic answers only, like regarding password reset, VPN, or maybe software center malware, BitLocker, Teams.
Jyoti Gupta: security incidents okay so I want to train my model like base model so that it can give company specific company specific answers okay like it will answer properly okay so if I show you my front end in front end like I have put up some questions okay if you see here like how to reset your password if I click here let's say okay and if someone send it
Jyoti Gupta: It will ask the… it will give you the answer for that.
Jyoti Gupta: Okay, and also you can choose the model also from here, whether you want to see the DPO answer, whether you want to see the SFT stage, whether you want to see the PACE model. Okay, talking about the data set, basically how much, if you see here, okay, let me go to my slide pack. I have taken around 55 paragraphs.
Jyoti Gupta: And total, if I go here, I have taken this base model, ANSIL COIN 2.4, 1.5B, instruct BNB 4-bit, okay? And in the non-instruction set, I have 55 paragraphs. In stage 2, I have 120 QA and pairs. And in stage 3, if you look, I have 60 chosen and, I mean, prompt chosen rejected samples.
Jyoti Gupta: OK, I can show you a sample also for this. Like in my front end, if you go to data set explorer, OK, you can see here like in stage two, I have created this kind of data instruction and response, instruction and response. And in if you go to stage three, it will be this kind of data prompt chosen rejected. OK, and if I go with the Loraset configuration, then I have I have used
Jyoti Gupta: these kind… these configurations, like, 16 is the rank, so alpha is the, like, scaling factor is 32, prop out is this much, trainable parameters are this much, and if you… if you want to see the hyperparameters, how much learning grade backs…
Jyoti Gupta: effective epox, how much I have… I did that work, and
Jyoti Gupta: In terms of VRAM also, I did these things, like how much GBIS we have used, how much VRAM we have used.
Jyoti Gupta: OK, and if I and also I want to show you, I created the evaluation matrix also like how much correctness we have. One second, let me show how much correctness, how much accuracy corresponding to different models we have. See different colors. If you go with the base model, it has gray color, it has SFT blue color, it is DPO in green color. OK, so corresponding to
Jyoti Gupta: every factor, what is how much rating it has.
Jyoti Gupta: you can see here, okay? Like, SFT versus GPO, how much improvement is there, even you can see that. Also, I have covered one more major point also, corresponding to every question, what I have written, what are the different stages answered, so you can see next.
Jyoti Gupta: You can click here and you can see different things also. Overall score, how much, how much improvement got increased, how much trainable parameters are there, how much security it has, it has all the answers. Now coming back to my slide, I have covered this point also, like sir, you have mentioned that we can use a ORPO trainer also. So why I have used
Jyoti Gupta: TTO, not ORPO. I have covered that point also because for a smaller data set, okay, if you have already did SFT, right, again, if you come, what is ORPO? It is nothing but combination of SFT and preference alignment. So again.
Jyoti Gupta: again, we need to do the SFT. It's kind of a repeatable. And also, since my… I am working on only 60 pair of data set, so it is good to go ahead with the DPO. That's why I have used DPO and not ORPO. So, basically, I have written the factors also, why I have preferred the DPO over the RPO.
Jyoti Gupta: OK, and also I have covered one major point here. If you see here, we have different models, right? And corresponding to different models, what is the MMU percentage? MMU means like if you have a certain model, it will cover different topics like history, social economics, GK, it will cover around 9700 topics, right? So how much a particular model can answer your base? I mean.
Jyoti Gupta: how can answer your problem right so that is this this much percentage and for other models I also have written the percentage and Hellasweg is nothing but how much the model like Quinn is able to complete your unfinished sentence so that percentage I also have given so I've covered these factors also and among them this was the best model
Jyoti Gupta: If you see now, if I coming back to the output, I have pasted my output here and how much loss it has. Like if I ran on collab only and if you go with the stage one, this was the output and this much time it has taken and this much loss it has given. For stage two, it has this much loss, this much time and this much VRAM it has.
Jyoti Gupta: If you corresponding, if you go ahead with the stage 3, then it has this much loss, and this much percent time it has taken, and this much VRAM is there, okay? And finally, we have the inference data set, so if you see here, like, it is giving answers corresponding to everything. And also.
Jyoti Gupta: Like, in my PPT, I have pasted that also. Like, I have created the front end also, and the basic slide also.
Jyoti Gupta: And if I go ahead with and if I go ahead with the code, so if you see here known instruction data set, I ran in the collab. OK, what I did in the in the instruction set and data set, I have installed the basic libraries like unslow TRL, PEFT, accelerate bits and pipes and post that I did. I imported the required libraries for that post that I did the chunking of the data like I opened the I opened
Jyoti Gupta: it, I cleaned it and I chunked it. After chunking it, I have basically I have built the required data set in the form of the hugging phase, right? After hugging phase, I have declared the LoRa configuration. Post the LoRa configuration, I have trained it, okay, I like training and all and post that post training, I have pushed my model into the inference mode so that it can get the required, it can
Jyoti Gupta: generate the required answers. Post doing that, I have gone to another one, like training instruction data set, sorry, instruction adapter, one second.
Jyoti Gupta: This is non-instruction. Let me go to instruction 1.
Jyoti Gupta: Yep.
Jyoti Gupta: Post that instruction, what I did, I again, I have installed the required libraries, whatever it is written like on slot and I imported them. After importing them, I like I created the Laura configuration. I declared the Laura configuration post declaring the Laura configuration. I I I if you see here step first.
Jyoti Gupta: Yeah, okay. So, I did the training, like, I, I did, created the configuration parameters for SFT. Post-declaring the configuration, I started the fine-tuning, okay? Then I saved the required files. After success saving the required files, I pushed that model into inference mode, and I've created certain test questions, which it can answer.
Jyoti Gupta: And post that, final one is the DPO alignment, okay? So…
Jyoti Gupta: Sorry, preference alignment. For that, I installed the required libraries and then import… I did the imports, okay? And again, same thing, like, I have built the dataset, I have declared the configuration for the LoRa.
Jyoti Gupta: POSAT, I trained it, started training, and then saved the required files.
Jyoti Gupta: Post that, after doing all these things, I went into the inference mode, like, I created the last file. So, in the last file, like, I… whatever the models I have created, I called all the… all the models here, if you see here, okay? And I passed the required prompt.
Jyoti Gupta: Okay, after like I have passed in this form, like role should be system content, content should be my prompt role user and content should be the question. Then I applied the chat template like conversational AI kind of thing. After doing the configuration AI thing, I dragged my, I put my demo questions, whatever the demo questions I have want to give, then it has gone in loop. Okay, if I want to exit it, then I can simply
Jyoti Gupta: Right, exit, and yeah.
Jyoti Gupta: This is how my project is.
Sunny: Oh, that's, great, Jyoti. So, you have done a lot of things.
Bhargav A: Okay.
Sunny: And mainly the UI side, basically, you put a lot of effort. So how did you create that, Jyoti? So the first question, basically, which I would like to ask you, how have you, like, created the UI and all? So have you taken the help of the Claude, ChatGPT, or…
Jyoti Gupta: Good job.
Sunny: Copilot you have used.
Jyoti Gupta: No, sir. I haven't used what you have mentioned in the assignment. I have used Bob.
Sunny: Okay.
Jyoti Gupta: Yep.
Jyoti Gupta: So, I have created my dataset, I did all the things post that, when I am ready with everything, like output, everything was working, I just given the simple prompt in the Bob, and it has given me the full.
Sunny: Exact.
Jyoti Gupta: Full website. I have passed all the files into the IPMPOP. I have the free credits, basically, so I use them.
Sunny: So, you had to create it, basically, and you have used that specific AI tool for creating this UI and all, correct? Yeah. Great. So, that's a good work, Jyoti, you demonstrated in a very well manner, and the result and all, basically, see, whenever we work in a real time, correct? So, we always look into that results.
Sunny: Okay, whether this model is giving the correct result or not, you even demonstrated that over here, right? Even Vala has represented, but his solution was more towards the notebook and the result-oriented, that was also good, but yeah, it is, like, more structurally oriented.
Jyoti Gupta: Sir, my… if you see here, if you see here in the collab, how do I reset my password? Go to your company's account management. Everyone can see the answer here, okay? Even if you see in terms of training and all, okay? I did that training. You can see here.
Jyoti Gupta: Successfully on slot like corresponding to every file I.
Jyoti Gupta: I've saved that output in the collab, see.
Sunny: Mmh.
Jyoti Gupta: How much dataset, how much chunking is there, right? How much dataset examples are there, okay? And how much time it has taken in the base model with unsloth, everything. Like, before our session, I ran it one more time, so that I should not take more time in giving my demo.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Jyoti Gupta: Yep.
Sunny: If you see here, it is 100%. Inferencing is also very fast, and I think it is because of the Ansel. Ansel is helping a lot over here, right? Yeah. Great.
Jyoti Gupta: Yeah, yeah. If you see here, after every file, I have written the summary of that particular file also. Like, if someone wants to see the collab also, they can get easily what I have used and what I have not used.
Jyoti Gupta: So, corresponding to everything, I have saved the output also. Like, corresponding to step 3, what is output, how many examples are there, how much trainable parameters are there, right? So, even in training, how much time it has taken, and if you see the step, like, how much, what is the training loss is there. So, I've written here everything.
Jyoti Gupta: Like, it has got to…
Sunny: And, where you hosted this application?
Sunny: You, you're just running in the local itself, right? You're, live, you're live.
Jyoti Gupta: I just… I just… I'm just running in the local. I haven't hosted anywhere, yeah.
Sunny: Okay, that's great. So, yeah, good work, Jyoti, very good work. So, now the chat is open for everyone, right? So, if someone is asking any sort of a question or having any doubt, you can clear over there. Got it?
Jyoti Gupta: Sure.
Sunny: And even you can share your code base inside the chat, and yeah, let's give chance to another person, and let's look into another solution also. Yeah, thank you.
Jyoti Gupta: Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you, Jyoti. Thank you for the, like, presentation. Now, next is the Mandeep. Mandeep Morton, please go ahead with the solution.
Mandeep Motan: Hello, sir.
Mandeep Motan: Share my screen.
Sunny: Yeah, you can share. Jyoti, you can stop sharing, okay?
Mandeep Motan: Okay, hang on.
Mandeep Motan: So is my screen visible?
Sunny: No, it is not visible.
Mandeep Motan: Fair enough.
Mandeep Motan: video.
Mandeep Motan: Sir, could you guide me? Where was the screen share button?
Sunny: That arrow button, can you see that share arrow button?
Mandeep Motan: Yes.
Sunny: Add below your screen, or raise hand.
Mandeep Motan: Yeah, yeah.
Sunny: Okay, something like… yeah, just click on the share, and then,
Sunny: Click the… sorry, share the entire screen, okay? Don't share the single screen, got it?
Mandeep Motan: Opposite.
Sunny: Sure.
Mandeep Motan: It's using those content on this program.
Mandeep Motan: Bias, yes.
Mandeep Motan: So, sir, my screen's being shared.
Mandeep Motan: Hello?
sumit das: Yes.
Sunny: Yeah, it is, it is.
sumit das: But it is smaller, actually. Can you make it a bit bigger?
Mandeep Motan: Bye.
Sunny: I think you are using a monitor, is it?
Mandeep Motan: No, sir. My laptop.
Sunny: Okay, just maximize the screen.
Mandeep Motan: Next slides.
Sunny: Maximize means, just click on the maximize option.
Mandeep Motan: Is it no longer set now?
Sunny: Yeah, it's, fine, you can go ahead. Yeah, the timer is start now, you can go ahead.
Mandeep Motan: Yes.
Mandeep Motan: So, like, normal, sir.
Mandeep Motan: So, hi people, I'm Dean Morton.
Mandeep Motan: So before I start my presentation.
Mandeep Motan: I want you to all remind of these two both famous tech world cases.
Mandeep Motan: One is of this Air Canada chatbot case, and one is of this Chevy dealership AI chatbot case.
Mandeep Motan: Sir, my screen visible now?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, it is visible, sir. Go ahead, please. I'll stop you if anything goes wrong, okay? Don.
Mandeep Motan: Okay, thank you, sir. So, let me give you a very short summary of what happened in these two cases, as Sanisa also told us about these two cases. So, in February 2024, a Canadian resident named Jake Muford sued Air Canada after inquiring about their
Mandeep Motan: Online AI chatbot, the chatbot said to edit a refund within the 90 days of the fees after they have filed the charges. But actually, that was not in the internal policy of the AI flight.
Mandeep Motan: And in another case of the Chavro dealership.
Mandeep Motan: They deployed an underlying GPT wrapper on their website, and within hours, users manipulated the board into agreeing to sell a very costly car of their own. A $60,000 car for, like, $1 car.
Mandeep Motan: And so these aren't just prompt engineering bugs. These are fundamental alignment areas. So this is from where I got the idea of building this.
Mandeep Motan: No.
Mandeep Motan: This is the where from I got the idea of building a customer support specialist AI board.
Mandeep Motan: Because the base model out of the box is just people-pleasing side of base model, and it's more of a hallucination one. It ignores basic company policies to align with the customer support, and I thought this would cost companies lots of money and a waste of time in the legal matters.
Mandeep Motan: So, I built this.
Mandeep Motan: Card rental, so let me show you the…
Mandeep Motan: So, to be honest, I built this using Jambini AI as my Claude subscription finished last month, and I was out of tokens, so this is just a basic dashboard.
Mandeep Motan: So.
Mandeep Motan: Yeah, as you can see here, the basic Llama model, it was doing system prompt leakage a lot of time I have seen.
Mandeep Motan: But our DPO-aligned models are…
Mandeep Motan: It followed all the company policies which I gave it in the prompt in Jinjing, and it gave me a correct response as my alignment.
Mandeep Motan: I'm still not able to…
Mandeep Motan: Some kind of this.
Sunny: So, are you facing some issue, Mandeep?
Mandeep Motan: Sir, there is, Sir, this is Zoom show webinar and this whole tab coming over.
Sunny: Do one thing, stop share, and again share that, okay? Stop share, and then again share.
Sunny: Here.
Anil Venkatrao: Yeah, Sami, if he has issue, I can go ahead All on me.
Sunny: Are you… have you opened your camera as well, Mandeep?
Mandeep Motan: No, sir, cameras off Yep.
Sunny: Yeah, I, I.
Mandeep Motan: She might have dropped.
Sunny: camera, now it is fine. Yeah, now you can go ahead. Yeah, it is working.
Mandeep Motan: So you can see my GitHub rep.
Sunny: Yeah, it is visible, and mandeep, you have 6 minutes of time, so just…
Mandeep Motan: Sure.
Sunny: Yeah, just, go quickly.
Mandeep Motan: Let me give a fast answer. So this is what you sent me to build in the assignment. So this is my basic readme file here. I have mentioned the cart Intel AI. It is a customer.
Mandeep Motan: Boat, fastest boat, and I've used Lalama 3.1, 3.2, 1 billion model.
Mandeep Motan: So here is a basic architecture overview using the customer. I have done the stage one in non-instruction fine tuning, then the supervised fine tuning, then merge the trained weights and in the DPU alignment. At the end, it's just a radio basic dashboard.
Mandeep Motan: So, the dataset details… Here I can show you the data set.
Mandeep Motan: So this is a basic data set which I got generated from Groq. This one I got generated from Groq synthetically and this one I got generated by Gemini. So this is a raw data set.
Mandeep Motan: So here you can see in my known instruction fine tuning, I mounted drive because I was saving all the stuff on the drive because I don't know why, but mine was disconnecting and again and again. So I extracted and processed a raw data set from those synthetically generated files.
Mandeep Motan: This is one for PDF extraction and processing of the data. This one is for the…
Mandeep Motan: txt this one function is for the txt file processing data then here I've processed both the files and created a single high quality corpus for the
Mandeep Motan: For the non-section fine-tuning, you can see in the my process dataset.
Mandeep Motan: This is one for the known instruction data set.
Mandeep Motan: So you can see this is a single file created by that function for the no instruction fine tuning.
Mandeep Motan: So here I initialized all the base Llama model and initialized the LoRa hyperparameters.
Mandeep Motan: So here I started that, here I started the dataset construction and tokenization, and here…
Mandeep Motan: Yeah. Yeah, the training started. Yeah, here's the training phase started.
Mandeep Motan: Then I didn't merge the model weights at the end, I just saved it into the Google Drive, then coming to the non-instruction fine-tuning.
Mandeep Motan: Supervised fine tuning, right? So, yeah, I did the basic mounting drive.
Mandeep Motan: So, here I loaded the…
Mandeep Motan: Yeah, my first stage 1 fine-tuned model from my Google Drive, where I saved the trained weights, then I merged into the main base Llama model.
Mandeep Motan: Then loaded the QLara target modules.
Mandeep Motan: So… through I can show you my data set. I'm searching data set. Yeah.
Mandeep Motan: So I generated this dataset synthetically using Gemini, but I used it from the Hugging Face BitText customer support. But here is that I have edited this dataset so that it is more aligned towards a single company of a company which I created on ArrowCart something.
Mandeep Motan: So, it has a bit of the company policies aligned with it.
Mandeep Motan: So he can see.
Mandeep Motan: All the parameters are assigned here. So the batch size and the gradient decrement and here the training.
Mandeep Motan: And… basic inference. You can see it is giving the inquiry and the operational response. It is telling if
Mandeep Motan: The answers are right or not. So it is a comparison of basic and base model and the SFT model.
Mandeep Motan: Yeah, okay.
Mandeep Motan: so as you can see base model actually didn't responded as I wanted it but our supervised fine-tuning model it do responded very improved than the base model then I merged the trained weights to the stage one and stage two merged weights then I uploaded it to push it to the hugging face so you can see my
Mandeep Motan: Hugging face rapple.
Mandeep Motan: Then coming to the DPO alignment model, sir, this is the dataset for the preference.
Mandeep Motan: That's it. So yeah, this one also I got generated synthetically from Grok. Yeah, this one I got generated by Grok and here is the
Mandeep Motan: Notebook for… Here I loaded the SFT model directly from the hugging face.
Mandeep Motan: Attached new LoRa adapters for DPO training.
Mandeep Motan: Here I loaded the dataset and prepared it for training.
Mandeep Motan: Yeah, here I've used a DPO trainer and DPO configs. So I have set the parameter. Yeah, they all are simple. Yeah, I haven't done any much of the changes.
Mandeep Motan: So here all the training was done. Then the basic inference. So I merged the weights and pushed it to save the trained weights into Google Drive and pushed the main merged model to the hugging face. So here this is my last model and I used this for the inference in the last.
Mandeep Motan: So here you can see this is my inferencing. So here I've loaded the base Llama model.
Mandeep Motan: And my end tuned, my stage 3 DPO fine tuned model, which I pushed at the end in the hugging phase.
Mandeep Motan: So here you can see my basic Chrome template. So it is the inference logic and it is my basic Gradio UI.
Mandeep Motan: I got it all made by Zamini.
Mandeep Motan: And I think it's still Ramin's view, yeah.
Mandeep Motan: So.
Mandeep Motan: One thing I noted was that it was leaking a lot of system code.
Mandeep Motan: So, you can see my DPU-aligned model, it followed the policies which I gave it in here in the system prompt while in the prompt engineering, and it was following all.
Mandeep Motan: Here, like, I can ask it.
Mandeep Motan: for the comparison.
Mandeep Motan: And fencing was very slow.
Mandeep Motan: Oh, it's about 3.
Mandeep Motan: I think I've done something wrong with the base model, so that's why there isn't a whole response. But here you can see the DPO-aligned model, its response is very improved.
Mandeep Motan: I understand you're looking for, and we can see so coming towards the Where's the other shoots?
Mandeep Motan: So… oops.
Mandeep Motan: But it's.
Sunny: You hosted over the Hugging Face space, right?
Mandeep Motan: No, sir, it wasn't allowing me to host, it was saying the model is big, and even I tried the 500 million parameter one, it didn't allow me to host that also. Okay.
Sunny: Okay.
Mandeep Motan: I'm gonna.
Sunny: Radio UI, and you're just starting in the local itself, correct? That…
Mandeep Motan: Yes, in the, Google collab.
Sunny: Google Collab. Got it.
Mandeep Motan: Yeah, just half an hour before the class, I started it all. And that even my two accounts, it isn't allowing me to use GPU. This is my third account for using GPU.
Sunny: No.
Mandeep Motan: So here you can see the final evaluation. So here I've asked 10 questions, as you said, to ask, and there it's a lot of difference.
Sunny: Oh.
Mandeep Motan: Most of the time, DPU model answer was very improved, but sometimes SFT model was also working well. There was hallucination, but it was controlled. Here you can see basic evaluation metrics.
Sunny: Oh my.
Mandeep Motan: I got it all generated by Gemini when I gave all these questions and answers to Gemini.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Mandeep Motan: Most of the time, DPO model was working perfect.
Sunny: Model you are using as a base model?
Mandeep Motan: Base Llama models are 3.21 billion parameters.
Sunny: Okay, okay, got it, got it.
Sunny: Yeah, your solution is also great, sir, because you also put a lot of effort, Mandeep, and I can see a lot of, basically, back and forth over here.
Sunny: And even you created your UI for the demonstration. So yeah, that's great, Mandeep. So what was the biggest challenge you faced while you were developing that, this one?
Mandeep Motan: Actually, in the very starting I faced was the dataset processing because the dataset which I got generated synthetically, my base script which I got generated by Gemini to process the dataset, it wasn't processing it the way I wanted. So I had to manually edit those old scripts so that they can, you know, basically all the way I wanted to process and prepare the dataset for the non-instruction fine tuning. So that was my first one.
Mandeep Motan: And at the end also, that was the TRL-related configurations, I had problems, so I had to…
Mandeep Motan: do some back and forth with Gemini, and I solved it also.
Sunny: Yeah, that's right. See, your data set is a unique one. You selected a very good problem statement for fine-tuning, okay?
Mandeep Motan: Who'.
Sunny: So, that's really great, Mandeep. So, yeah, thank you for the representation. Sorry, I have a time constraint, so you spoke around 13 minutes, but yeah, you did a good job. I really appreciate it.
Mandeep Motan: Thank you, s.
Sunny: Yeah. So we'll go for the result at the end, don't worry, Mandeep, okay?
Mandeep Motan: Sure, sure, sure.
Sunny: Okay? Sure. So, yeah.
Sunny: Fine guys, I think, we can go for the next, representing, let me call out the name. Sumit, please go ahead.
sumit das: Yeah. Let me just share my screen.
Sunny: Yeah. And after the summit, even I lined up a couple of more people, like Gaurav, Anil, and Dipti is there, Mithul is there. So guys, be ready with the solution, okay?
Sunny: So, I'm starting time also, but, please keep the time constant in your mind, and please go ahead, okay?
sumit das: Yeah.
sumit das: Can you see my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, I can see.
sumit das: Yeah, so, yeah, hi, everyone. So, yeah, so this is the, this is the assignment that I did. It's, like, IT help desk assignment, assistance with the three-stage LLM fine-tuning.
sumit das: So…
sumit das: basically, here, I have, like, kind of developed an AIS… domain-specific AI assistant, using, TinyLlama, 1.1 billion parameter, and then… on Sloth and, Laura, the kind of…
sumit das: like, tech stack that I, have used. So here, the, like, the approach, or these three, like, three-stage fine-tuning workflow that I have worked on is kind of, like, first, non-instruction.
sumit das: fine-tuning, and then supervised SFT, and then DPO. So… so these are…
sumit das: like, okay, so, this is basically the three-stage, like, pipeline. In the base model, it's basically Tiny Llama 1.1 billion parameters. So in the stage one, non-instruction fine-tuning, here, I have used
sumit das: raw IT, documents, and then in the stage 2, supervised fine-tuning, where I've used, Alpaca, format instruction
sumit das: response data set. That data set I got from, like, yeah, from, Hugging Face data set, and then the last, stage, stage 3, that is basically, DPO, so there I have used, preference data set.
sumit das: So that dataset, I, kind of, like, created from the, like, from this non-instruction dataset, this raw dataset, that, from that one, I created using, like, LLM. So, yeah, so…
sumit das: So this is basically the approach, so let me just, give you… Just a second.
sumit das: Yeah. So… Oh.
sumit das: Yeah, so this is my, repo structure. Here you can, get to see, like, what is the structure that I have used. So this is, like, in the data folder, I have kept all the, different kind of data, raw data, and then instruction
sumit das: dataset, and then, yeah, that, instruction dataset, and the, DPO dataset, and in the notebook, I have all these, three, notebooks that,
sumit das: raw, like, non-instruction fine-tuning notebook, and the instruction fine-tuning notebook, and the DPO notebook, and as well as an evaluation notebook as well. In the report, like, folder, we have… I have the final
sumit das: evaluation and stage-wise evaluation as well. And in the scripts.
sumit das: In the non-instruction dataset, raw dataset, I have created some, like, a scraper to scrape the dataset, like, from web, and in the SRC, I have the inference, like, script.
sumit das: And, model in this model folder, like, though I don't have the model here, all the models are there in
sumit das: the Colab, because those models are pretty big, so that's… that's why I did not keep those things in the model. And in these docs, I have all the different architecture diagrams and different, other, like, each stage-specific documents and all those things I have kept it here.
sumit das: Yeah, so, let me just go to… The… just a second.
sumit das: Yeah, so,
sumit das: Yep.
sumit das: So, data set wise.
sumit das: So here, as I mentioned, like I have like created dataset for means non-instruction dataset and then so like how I have prepared the non-instruction dataset so all those details I have kept in these individual documents such such as for so like what is the what is the what is my reason for
sumit das: like, choosing this domain that I have kept in, this domain selection in this document, and in this non-instruction fine-tuning, non-instruction data set.
sumit das: Here, what are the domains, or what are the, like, kind of documents I have, like, selected? Those, like, all the topics and all those things I have kept there in this, document.
sumit das: And, like, as I mentioned, I, like, extracted those documents, from web, and I created… I developed some scraper to, like, scrape those data, and those data are basically… those data are basically some of the…
sumit das: like, help me documentations and other, technical documentation from these, like, these sites, like GitHub.
sumit das: And then Docker, Linux, and VS Codes, and all those different README documentation. From there, I kind of…
sumit das: like, got the data, and for that, I created the scraper, and all those scrapers and everything, like.
sumit das: cleaning the data and splitting paragraphs and everything. All those things are there in the, like, like, in the, like, in the scripts, like, yeah, in the scripts, in this, like, folder.
sumit das: And…
sumit das: So for all these things, I have, like, different, different scripts for that one. And finally, the data that I got out of that one is the raw data set.
sumit das: that I have in this non-instruction data. So here you can see all these different non-instruction data sets, and that I have used in this non-instruction data set. I have used
sumit das: in the, the notebook. This notebook is basically this non-instruction fine-tuning notebook that you can get in this notebook, like, in this notebook. Here, I have followed, basically the basic steps, whatever
sumit das: Sunny, you have, learned us, like, you have taught us to, like, like, do all these things, I fine-tune it. I have, like, I have followed those steps only, I have not, I have not, like, tweaked or anything much on that one, the basic steps, all those things I kind of followed.
sumit das: And then once the non-instruction fine-tuning is done, so then I went for the instruction fine-tuning. So for that instruction fine-tuning, like, I have used
sumit das: Like, to create the data set.
sumit das: like this is the kind of approach for creating the instruction fine tuning data. So for that, I used like one of the Kaggle data set. So yeah, so from that Kaggle, so that's a multilingual data set. So from that multilingual data set, I kind of filtered some of the data based on certain filters. There are many different variant of the data among
sumit das: that I kind of based on my problem statement I filtered the data and from there I got around like around 500 like rows of the data and then and how I selected the data that be that actually based on the domain selection whatever domain I kind of selected and there I kind of like I had specific some of the specific areas I kind
sumit das: of, like, choose to work on, such as password research, and other, some of, some of the relevant things. So, based on those, domain, like, or those domains and subdomains, I kind of filtered this data from this Kaggle dataset. And on top of this, Kaggle dataset, I create, I added some, like,
sumit das: handcuffed it handcuffed it in the sense I got some kind of like other data sets generated by LLM as well in that way total number of data points was around like 600 six yeah 615 or 620 total data points for the instruction supervised fine-tuned data set and I used that data set for supervised fine-tuning
sumit das: in my supervised fine-tuning this, like, notebook to build the model. And then I, like, run that evaluation on that one. And then finally, on the DPO as well, I created the data for
sumit das: Yeah, so here I created the data for the DPO. Here, total number of data points I used was around 60 data points, like, in the same format that accept-reject in that format. So for that one, I used
sumit das: the raw, data, like, the raw data that I, like, created, that I got, like, fetched from WIP. Based on that, I created this data set, and then finally, I, created, I built that, like, DPO alignment
sumit das: approach based on that one. And then, finally, to run an evaluation on this one, I have a separate data set that is called evaluation question. So so these 10 questions. So based on that, I did the evaluation for all these 3 things, base model and then supervised fine tuned model and Dpo
sumit das: like, DPO-based model, and then you can see, the… so this is the, like.
sumit das: overall comparison, the final evaluation. So, you can see for
sumit das: So these questions for these 10 questions, I ran the evaluation and that evaluation was like the entire fine tuning, all these fine tunings were done in Google Colab, but this evaluation I didn't run in my local and these, all these things were done based on these like criteria, correctness, helpfulness, domain acquisition, all those things. And these were primarily
sumit das: done using LLM as judge, and yeah, it was primarily… I used Claude code for this one, and based on that, it, like, gave the… gave a kind of comparison for that one, how… in how many cases
sumit das: SFT ran like SFT's output is good in how many cases DPO's output is good in that way. So since I used very basic configuration for that one, only 30 like iterations and the number of iterations and all those things are pretty small. So that's why the improvement that I got from SFT was like not that much. And since
sumit das: DPO is kind of… it is based… it actually kind of uses the output of SFT, so since SFT's output is not that good, so that's why DPO is also not going
sumit das: that much of good whatever we are kind of expecting I can improve all those things by by like doing further training of that one so based on those 10 10 questions you can see like in four cases SFT is output outright winner DPO is winner in one cases and rest of the things are almost all three models are kind of same so in that way so some of the so these are some of the evaluation criteria
sumit das: And, these are my findings. So, as I mentioned, DPO did not improve
sumit das: on SFT, like, on SFT in this run, so since, like, it is purely based on the SFT output, and these are some of the recommended steps to rerun the DQ and SFT on a larger, like, max steps and all those different things. Yeah, so, yeah, mostly this one.
sumit das: Yeah, so this is mostly my, yeah, my work. I think I have kind of used 10 minutes or something.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, that's also great, Sumit. I think you followed the complete class-based approach, and your solution is also very neat and clean, which I can see, right? Yeah. So, you can share this GitHub link in the chat, so that other person also can go through with this entire solution, right?
Sunny: Because what I can see, whatever I have mentioned in the assignment, you follow the same thing point by point, and this is, like, really a great, organized solution. Okay?
sumit das: Yeah, yeah.
Sunny: Yeah. Well, but,
sumit das: So what I… so what I kind of tried is that instead of going for the best solution or something like that, I tried to follow the structure, like, I can improve these things.
sumit das: by, like, by input, like, giving a huge number of data points, or running it for a very number of, like, number of iterations, or if I get larger GPU and all those things, but the purpose of this assignment is to kind of
sumit das: understand the flow and what are the steps basically needs to, we need to follow to, give a better solution. So that is the kind of thing that I tried to follow, yeah.
Sunny: Mmhm
Sunny: No, yeah, that's what I'm saying. You prepare the complete base, and on top of it, basically, you can do more brainstorming, okay?
sumit das: Yep, ye.
Sunny: Thank you, thank you, Sumit, for the representation. I noted your name, so, yeah, thank you.
sumit das: I'll share the GitHub link, I'll share the GitHub link in.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, definitely you can share, and even you can ask some questions as well, if someone is having any sort of doubt, you can answer over there, okay?
sumit das: Yeah, yeah, thanks. Yeah, thanks all.
Sunny: Thank you, sir. Thank you. You can stop sharing.
Sunny: Now the next one is the Bhargav, Bhargav, Gaurav. Anyone is there, guys? Deepthi, Bhargav, Gaurav, so you can go ahead with your presentation.
Bhargav A: Can you hear me?
Bhargav A: Margo here.
Sunny: Yeah, Bhagav, please go ahead.
Bhargav A: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah, sure.
Sunny: So, just a second…
sumit das: You just… you can kick me out, I'm not able to, like, stop sharing. Yeah, maybe…
Sunny: Yeah, I can, just a second.
Sunny: Dinner break. Guys, in today's session, I think we don't have any break, okay? So if you wanted to have your dinner and all, you can have, because today we are not learning anything, right? Just a demonstration. So watch out that, okay? While having your dinner.
Sunny: Okay, yeah, please go ahead, Varga.
Sunny: Okay, I think Bhargav is not here, just a second.
Sunny: Barry, can you please raise the hand? If you are there, then…
Anil Venkatrao: Sunny, I can go if he's not available then.
Sunny: No, I think by mistake, I… remove it… remove him from the panelists, so that's why.
Sunny: I'm not quite…
Bhargav A: Yeah, something happened there, I think. It came over.
Sunny: Thank you.
Bhargav A: Can you hear me, right?
Sunny: Yeah, I can hear you. Please go ahead, Varun. Okay.
Bhargav A: Okay.
Bhargav A: I'm sharing my screen.
Sunny: Yeah, please go ahead.
Bhargav A: Okay.
Bhargav A: Okay, thanks, thanks everyone. Good morning, good evening, good afternoon, wherever you are.
Bhargav A: I'm going to present my solution. It doesn't take more than 5 minutes.
Bhargav A: so… I'll go with the… the entry-in solution.
Bhargav A: For the product I developed recently. It's called Cactus Source Peach. It's nowhere…
Bhargav A: to promote my product here, but I just want to share that, how it can be used, the potential of it.
Bhargav A: I created a chatbot.
Bhargav A: So, behind the scenes… That the model that is trained will be giving answers to us.
Bhargav A: So, I just want to demonstrate that, starting with hello.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, please go ahead. We are, hearing you. If anything goes wrong, I'll interrupt you, okay? Don't worry. Please go.
Bhargav A: Okay, yeah, so it says that, hello, can you assist you today?
Bhargav A: I'll ask a couple of questions, based on the training that is… that is made.
Bhargav A: So, couple of questions here.
Bhargav A: How do you sign up for an account in…
Bhargav A: Episode speech dot com. Right?
Bhargav A: So, it's a good answer to sign up, navigate to the register route, and fill out the registration form.
Bhargav A: The backend validate the email password complexity, then create a new profile in the speed users capable.
Bhargav A: So, a little bit about this product is, if you want to practice your speech, come here and then
Bhargav A: Take audio speech and then the behind the scenes AWS recognition and other AI models.
Bhargav A: We'll evaluate your speech and give you the report, within minutes, within seconds, actually, based on how long you gave a speech.
Bhargav A: So, it's instant feedback, instant evaluation of your speech.
Bhargav A: And let me give you one more question here. Can I use password reset if it is with the Google?
Bhargav A: So, whoever registered with Google, they can't reset the password, they have to deal with Google.
Bhargav A: And then come here and do the authentication here, right? So, for example,
Bhargav A: If you do here, I want to sign in here, right? Sign in one.
Bhargav A: want to sign in and continue to Google here, right?
Bhargav A: You can't reset password here, okay, that's what it
Bhargav A: I'll ask one more question. Probably this is the last question in order to save time.
Bhargav A: Do you need any specialized equipment to use tactusespeech.com? You don't need anything?
Bhargav A: Just needed a cam and microphone, as I mentioned.
Bhargav A: Just, after sign-up, you will see that, how to record your speech and proceed further, and evaluate, right? So, those are the things.
Bhargav A: So that's… that's a good model, okay
Bhargav A: Then, I'll go back a little bit, to go… how was my… How was my endpoint deployed?
Bhargav A: And… I want to mention this is all serverless.
Bhargav A: I…
Sunny: Parga, you, can you, okay, so you asked, after explaining this entire thing, can you, talk more about this, platform AI speech practice, okay, what kind of data set you are using, and what all, and tech you use in a backend, okay?
Bhargav A: Yes, yes, yes.
Sunny: Yes.
Bhargav A: Yeah, so sure. So I use the zombie model.
Bhargav A: So I said serverless because…
Bhargav A: I put this as out of 30 minutes activity, this standpoint will be down, so that you will not be charged. So for…
Bhargav A: The last 2 days, I spent around $3.27.
Bhargav A: I use the LLM engine.
Bhargav A: So the AWS VSC is 12.
Bhargav A: Using the NVIDIA A10G, one GPU, 24 gigabyte thing.
Bhargav A: It's authenticated. I created the authenticated one so that not everybody can use my
Bhargav A: Endpoint directly. If they don't, they will, they will pick it out if they don't provide an API key here.
Bhargav A: So this has a lot of challenges, faced, to… Oh, okay.
Bhargav A: to basically upload and create a point, endpoint for this, PAN 2.5 thing.
Bhargav A: And I did… these… have these models here, every stage I created.
Bhargav A: I create a Stage 1 mixture, and then upload into the Hugging Face, and then Stage 2, and then a final one.
Bhargav A: As you see, I started with a 5-vision model with the FEM.
Bhargav A: But it did not help me much. It had a lot of hallucination. Instead of going to my train data, it's going to the base model, or the current base model, and giving answers. Suppose if I ask for a price plan, it's going… it's giving the price plan for AWS, not for
Bhargav A: Not for my feature, practical feature, product.
Bhargav A: So, I found a lot of alication with 1.5 days, thing, then…
Bhargav A: I switched onto a zombie model, and I want to share that, what are the mistakes I did.
Bhargav A: During this process, that will be more helpful than going to the court.
Bhargav A: Right.
Bhargav A: Then I'll put the… I'll go to the…
Bhargav A: Okay, here, the self-domain, customer support, assistant, IT help desk.
Bhargav A: The target platform is package.speech.com.
Bhargav A: Business thing is, okay, there are a lot of things going on in the practice of speech.
Bhargav A: Then if you want, you want help, support, help, you can, use this chat bar.
Bhargav A: So, one thing I want to add is, fine-tune model as a backend for the chatbot is an expensive solution.
Bhargav A: Definitely, I'm not going that route, it's only for the assessment only. I'm going for a rag solution going forward, keeping the… keeping the chatbot as is.
Bhargav A: Because almost you're spending for $1 per hour, so if you run continuously.
Bhargav A: $24 per hour, which is $24 per day, which is not, which is not a…
Bhargav A: good solution from the cost perspective. So, definitely.
Bhargav A: After this assignment is over, I will shut down this backend, and I will switch on to the RAC solution.
Bhargav A: So…
Bhargav A: And some of the lessons I want to share, and I will leave some questions Q&A also going forward.
Bhargav A: So, the lessons I learned is I kept the five data files in the Google Drive, so that it can be accessed from the Google Colab, right? That is one thing.
Bhargav A: And base model, 1.5B, as I said, is not that successful for more hallucinations.
Bhargav A: And getting the response from the base model directly sometimes, so I switched on to.
Bhargav A: 7 billion parameter model, though the training takes longer.
Bhargav A: I stick not to that, okay? And then, saving to Hugging Face, the push-to-hub match more, method.
Bhargav A: So, I made a mistake in the beginning. I was only saving the model, but not the tokenizers.
Bhargav A: So when you don't have a tokenizer not made into the model, then you will not get your data into the model. So you'll get directly the answers from the base model, not from the fine tune model we had. So that is one lesson I got during my process.
Bhargav A: Then, like, what I found was in the… each step, each stage, I was…
Bhargav A: pushing the model to the Google Drive in the beginning, but that was taken for the next 50 minutes, because my model is very big.
Bhargav A: Right? Then I realized that…
Bhargav A: we're moving to the hugging phase faster. So, Google's Google App is… is… it is slow in…
Bhargav A: uploading the files to Google Drive, but it's very faster in saving the
Bhargav A: models to the hugging face. So I switched onto this, so that saves some time from 40 minutes to 10 minutes.
Bhargav A: and then pulling from hypothesis from the next stage. It's also the
Bhargav A: it's also faster. So, again, I made a mistake in pulling the model instead of weights, right? So, the weights from our data were not carried forward in the beginning, okay? So.
Bhargav A: I could not show the data because the code is gone, but this is a mistake I did. I was only loading the model, but not the…
Bhargav A: But not the… Tokenizers, okay?
Bhargav A: The third stage, DPU alignment, and the tuning of parameters, in the beginning, I took Magnum Steps 40.
Bhargav A: Then the learning rate is, 5.6, and the way I understood is…
Bhargav A: It is 40, and the learning rate is very slow. 40 is very quick time in order to learn this whole process. So the solution I got is, okay, do the maximum number of steps is 200 for the slow learning rate.
Bhargav A: Then, actually, it increases the accuracy.
Bhargav A: During the course. But I made this change, all these changes at once. I don't know which one's… which one changed the hallucination thing. This step…
Bhargav A: Let me take a minute for… gift apps, and…
Bhargav A: and also the sounding model, all those things I have done in the same day, and it's the same step, at the same time, I mean.
Bhargav A: then I didn't know which one helped, but for all… all these mistakes, the resolutions helped a lot.
Bhargav A: Again, deployment to Hugging Face. My, my, my product, this PracticeSourcePitch.com is, everything is, everything is serverless here.
Bhargav A: I have Lambda, which is serverless, API Gateway, which is serverless.
Bhargav A: And again, this hugging face is also serverless. So, I put this serverless to have this fast in control.
Bhargav A: And deployment is not straightforward. I have to confirm, really, the NVIDIA A10G for this, using VLLM engine.
Bhargav A: And again, as I said, CAP has indicated the API keys.
Bhargav A: I see some of the presentations, I put some… some people put the credentials in the, in the code.
Bhargav A: I… I don't suggest that credentials to put there. Read that… There is a… And,
Bhargav A: Colab, there is a secret manager you can use of that, instead of doing it.
Bhargav A: And again, reading the heading page also, I'm reading from the secrets.
Bhargav A: Again.
Bhargav A: These are the statutory details.
Bhargav A: I need to go to the rack solution for this problem.
Bhargav A: Okay, that concludes my presentation. If you want to go through the code, I can, but I can open for any Q&A.
Bhargav A: Hello?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, Bhargav. Sorry, I was speaking on mute. Okay, you are done, correct, Bhargav?
Bhargav A: Yes.
Sunny: Okay, okay, that's great. So, on a deployment site, you, like, really put some effort, okay, and even I can see the problem, and the domain selection is also very good.
Sunny: And basically, you are very honest about your mistake as well, so that's a good thing. I think you need to work more on your fine-tuning understanding, little more on the experimental design side, okay?
Sunny: evaluation quality and all, that is, like, fine, you will understand that part, but again, you portrayed everything in a very good way, mainly the problem statement in the deployment side, basically. So you hosted the… you are running it via Amazon API Gateway, correct? You are hitting the lambda, basically, that is making an inferencing, right?
Sunny: Like, which is reading a model and making an inference. Great, okay. So, inside the Lambda, so what code you written in the Lambda? Can you showcase that file?
Bhargav A: Oh, Lambda code is… Yeah, that's what it's Python
Bhargav A: Not here, it's not here, but I can show that to you.
Sunny: Yeah, no worries. You can keep in the same, basically, folder itself, okay? So we can look into that inferencing.
Bhargav A: No, thank you.
Sunny: Then over the lam.
Bhargav A: Yeah, that is a different product, that is in the previous report.
Sunny: -H.
Bhargav A: So, that's not shared anywhere.
Sunny: Okay.
Bhargav A: Actually, not this.
Bhargav A: The wrong one, I guess.
Bhargav A: Okay, so practice of speech. I have data assistance, I have…
Bhargav A: The back end and the front end.
Bhargav A: and I have a Lamb.
Sunny: So, it is a… this is a product you just created for the assignment? You're working before the assignment.
Bhargav A: No, no, no, no. The product is already there.
Sunny: Product was already there, right?
Bhargav A: The product is already there. I wanted to use this opportunity to learn this fine-tuning one. I never did fine-tuning before.
Bhargav A: I use this fine-tuning, and I want to integrate with my product.
Sunny: Thanks.
Sunny: Mmh.
Bhargav A: So and and as as I said, it's expensive thing. I'll I'll remove it after once this demo is over.
Sunny: Got it, got it. You just penetrated the fine-tuning inside your previous solution only, correct? In the previous project?
Bhargav A: Okay.
Sunny: Existing project, okay, okay. So, you'll just be sharing the fine-tuning code and all, correct? You will not be sharing this entire project, right?
Bhargav A: Yes, that's right. I just shared only this one.
Sunny: Oh.
Bhargav A: Spot.
Bhargav A: The learning and even their deployment also is not there, so it's… deployment is manual at this point, right?
Bhargav A: So… So, only these… the notebooks.
Sunny: Got it, got it. Okay, thank you, Bhargav, I got everything now. So, thank you for the demonstration, let's, give chance to the other folks also. Okay, I noted your name, yeah. So, thank you.
Bhargav A: Thank you, thank you.
Sunny: Yeah. So, Gaurav, Deepti, anyone is there, guys? You can go ahead now.
Gourab Swain: So.
Gourab Swain: Am I audible?
Sunny: Yeah, you're audible, Gaurav.
Gourab Swain: Oh, okay. Can I say my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, you can share the screen. Your time starts now. Please go ahead.
Gourab Swain: and dusk.
Gourab Swain: Okay, so… Is my screen is all visible?
Sunny: Yeah, it is visible.
Gourab Swain: Okay.
Gourab Swain: So, hey everyone, I am Gaurav, I am currently in my third year, so…
Gourab Swain: So, I just built this, place, place, placement preparation assistant, like,
Gourab Swain: Because I want to build something that actually know the domain, you know, like, know the actual DSA patterns and, like, priority of things, like, what kind of, kind of…
Gourab Swain: like, companies, like, product-based company and services company are asking the, asking about the topics and CGPA kind of things, and… yeah. The problem statement is, the problem statement is, I will, I will,
Gourab Swain: I find in a model, that helps students or, everything that, that are prepared, those are preparing for, preparing for interviews, that, that's, that's all. And…
Gourab Swain: Yeah, let's, and if I talk, if I explain about the architecture, it is, it's the same, same one everyone using, like.
Gourab Swain: I use the coin model, coin model, and the stage one, stage two, stage three are same. And after the final merger model, I also quantized the model into GGWF and, pushed into, also hosted that into.
Gourab Swain: Oh.
Gourab Swain: What it is, sir.
Gourab Swain: Well,
Gourab Swain: I also hosted that into, Hugging Face, and…
Gourab Swain: Yeah, it's, live in Hugging Face, and also I built a…
Gourab Swain: You can see, so that I can, everyone can use it. If I want to quick demonstrate this, so…
Gourab Swain: I just don't know how to negotiate my first offer later, and something like, that… something, so… it… it's… it's, giving the answer word by word, because I am setting something that in backend, so that, like, don't take much, delays.
Gourab Swain: And… And if I want to explain the data set, so let's talk about what.
Sunny: Can you again showcase your UI?
Gourab Swain: Yes, yes, yes, yes. This is actually done.
Sunny: Yeah, can you write a few more questions over here, if it is working right?
Gourab Swain: So, let's say, what kind… kind of DSA topic…
Gourab Swain: Here's a topic that I need to cover for, like, product-based companies. You can, give specific company names, like TCS or, anything. I just…
Gourab Swain: So… it will…
Gourab Swain: works. It, it have a good, accuracy as well, like, focus on areas. I have, I prepare the dataset in that way that, it, it, it's focused on a specific domain only. It's, only the, like.
Gourab Swain: The placement and interview proposed, like, here's a focus on area string, financial reporting, because, that's…
Gourab Swain: The product… product-based company are… are the basic kind of. So, the, like, the DPA entries are… you can make over later, and you can, ask it in… in anything. In my… in my GitHub profile, there, I have… I have, posted the link as well. So…
Gourab Swain: And then, if I want to explain the data set.
Gourab Swain: Team, that is.
Gourab Swain: Yes.
Gourab Swain: So…
Gourab Swain: So I generated all the data generically. So synthetically, I also generate all the data using Gpt. And what I what I feel like after generating it, the it have a many like for factual error, too generic, incomplete, unsafe, and I just like, I feel a lot of errors in that. So II just reset them, you know, by manually, manually.
Gourab Swain: I think it's something there, and…
Gourab Swain: And… and the code is, same as everything everyone is doing, but I don't wanna… so, like, if… still, still, I wanna… I wanna explain about it.
Gourab Swain: So if, the first… this is about all, the, configuration part, and…
Gourab Swain: Stage 1 and Stage 2, if I saw the, like, results, this is… this is the result, like, what kind of, training time it's taken, and final loss, and big VRAM used. And for Stage 2, for Stage 2, it's also… also, I have…
Gourab Swain: Then a good, documentation on top of that, and, like,
Gourab Swain: Also, I've made the inferencing all those stage-wise, after the stage 2, what it actually, like, giving me the answers.
Gourab Swain: And same as the DPU, same as for the DPU part.
Gourab Swain: And after that, I, I pushed all the… all the models and adapters in a single time, like, not after this model, this level, this level. I… after the complete… complete all three stages, and, pushed in directly… pushes in a single time, all the models and adapters.
Gourab Swain: And after that, I… I just… this is the code of our, posting to GGF, kind of, thing.
Gourab Swain: thing, and… I also… I also made this, Eval… evaluation…
Gourab Swain: evaluation code, that is actually, taking my answers of each mode, each level, and that is, and I, I take a George, I, I, I put a George as OpenAI, and see, he will care about that, like, what is the most,
Gourab Swain: Like, what is the best answer, and what is the, was,
Gourab Swain: And if I might as well… I'm a little…
Gourab Swain: So, if I want to show the,
Gourab Swain: Structs and base model violation. So, this is…
Gourab Swain: evaluation. So, this is here, the best answer is, like, I have to, to set the GPT 4.0 as a, as a, like, comparing, comparing this, all the models that they have.
Gourab Swain: Check, and out of those, he gave me the… which model… model you're performing best.
Gourab Swain: This is… this is, and… And… yeah, I… all… and the UA part is also kind of similar.
Gourab Swain: I can, like, everything is same, kind of, I just, launched something new, like, hosting, hosting the model and, building the web by using AI. So, something, there are far something, like, take some time, but, it's, yeah, it's actually worth it for, for me. So…
Gourab Swain: Yeah, that's it about it, and anything…
Gourab Swain: Or now, like, ask, you can ask, send it to me.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Like, it's a very great solution, Gaurav. As a college grade, I think you put a lot of effort, and your concepts is also very clear, okay? So, you did a good job, and I definitely would appreciate your work, right?
Sunny: And, you added something new, you added a, like, proper working UI over here, you hosted that UI, okay, and you are making a proper inferencing, and that is also working. So this is a very good workable solution, actually, right? And you added a very good line that everyone is showing a code, mine code is also same, there is no changes, but yeah.
Gourab Swain: Excellent.
Sunny: one more thing on top of that. That's, like, really good work. Okay, I will definitely appreciate your job. So, yeah, thank you. Thank you, Gaurav. Thank you for representing the solution, and please share this,
Sunny: a link, okay, in the chat, even the Vercel app, okay, and even this GitHub link, the raw code and all, so that everyone can also look into this entire solution, okay? So, in which college you are right now, currently?
Gourab Swain: Currently I'm in Odisha, like, this is a government college. It's a good college, but, not IIT, NIT, the top government college of the Odisha. Odisha University of Technology.
Sunny: Okay, okay. So you are, pursuing your, bachelor's from there, correct.
Gourab Swain: clean our third air, like, just compost it with the third air.
Sunny: Okay, okay.
Sunny: No, you did a very good job, Gaurav. As a 3rd grade student, I can see you put a lot of effort. I can compare yourself with me when I was in 3rd year, so I was just learning C++, and you are basically hosting the model, and you are doing the proper inferencing and all.
Gourab Swain: Yeah, he.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Thank you, Gaurav, thank you for the representation.
Gourab Swain: Thank you. Thank you.
Sunny: You finished it… finished within 10 minutes itself, so within 8 minutes, that's also it.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Next, one is the Deepthi Deepthi, you can go ahead now.
Deepti: Okay, I'm still sharing my screen. One second. Okay.
Deepti: Oh.
Deepti: Okay, can you see my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, I can see that.
Deepti: Okay.
Deepti: Okay, so…
Deepti: As part of this project, I have developed a HealthMate AI. So mainly the problem statement is that we have a general purpose LLM, but trying to get the generic answers by giving the instruction data as well as the preference data set.
Deepti: So, here we are trying to get,
Sunny: Sorry, Deepthi, I think your screen is not visible. Guys, anyone can see the screen? I don't think so, it's a black, Deepthi right now. Please share the screen again.
Deepti: Okay.
Gourab Swain: visible.
Sunny: Oh.
Deepti: Okay…
Sunny: Yeah, now it is visible.
Deepti: Okay.
Deepti: Okay, so yeah, so as part of this one, like I have developed HealthMate AI where we are actually getting actual healthcare related answers for the questions related to the healthcare things like we are asking general purpose questions. So what are the diabetic symptoms and these are the symptoms I have. So how it is actually or how
Deepti: many how much sleep we do we need so for that type of thing like I have developed this healthcare specific AI and so here in the solution actually like like when the user ask a question it actually goes to like in the AI chatbot then it actually hits the fine-tuned model and we will get the health
Deepti: Get a sponsor.
Deepti: So as for the pipeline, so if you see the training pipeline, I have used the base model, which is for the tiny llama. And then for that one, I have used SFT plus LoRA, like a structure training, like a LoRA training.
Deepti: And from there we got that healthcare assistant. Basically at this point at the SFT stage, the base model has a generic knowledge. After SFT, we got the healthcare assistant. And then I have applied that the DPO alignment where we have actually the preference data set. Then we got the final.
Deepti: help me TA.
Deepti: So, actually, like, here, we can see once we did the supervised fine-tuning, it's just a question and answer type, and, also why we used LoRa and, what is the reason.
Deepti: So, and after that, we move down to the direct preference optimization where we are actually giving the preference of what is a preferred, what, for example, if we see what causes high blood pressure, we have a preferred answer, rejected answer. In this way, we have trained the model, so we making sure that we are getting the outcome, which is the preferred one.
Deepti: So based on the models, like we have these three base models and then based on the models like where actually what which model gives you what exactly accurate information or which is giving the excellent information.
Deepti: For example, for this HealthMate AI, for the medical knowledge, always the base has the generic knowledge and trying to get the accurate response by giving the SFT as well as the DPO.
Deepti: In the same way, emergency guidance, some clinical terminology, context awareness, and response and patient guidance. So these are all, like, you can see, like, by the time we move from base to
Deepti: SFT, we will get some moderate answers, but we are trying to make it more advanced than we are using the DPO.
Deepti: so this is kind of like the evaluation result after the we perform the model response and everything so this is kind of like what we see the rating it got increased like for five out of ten questions it is giving more base model is okay but always we are trying to hit the good accuracy or good advanced
Deepti: Answers with the DPO Healthcare.
Deepti: So also, it's kind of like, I have also used, like, this HelpMate AI model, in, Hugging Face also, and I can show you that one too, so just a system architecture.
Deepti: They, in this technology stack, it's nothing but like what we just,
Deepti: used for the base model, and also the fine-tuning. We have used Ansler to make it load quickly in our Colab notebooks, and these are all the different UI. I have used Gradio for the UI, and also used… hosted in the Hugging Face.
Deepti: So, like, to… just wanted to show you the health, like, just, the live demo.
Deepti: I don't know, yeah. So live demo, like, this is, I have,
Deepti: Posted this health media in hugging faces. So this is kind of like a chat bot. I have already like to give these questions because it's going to take little time while in the during the demo. I just don't want to waste that time. So when I ask just like that heart attack symptoms, then after like 20 seconds, it is giving all the symptoms what we have for the heart attack.
Deepti: And also, like, if I just go, what should I do if I have a severe chest pain, then we should go to the hospital immediately, something like that, we are trying to make sure. And also, making sure we are giving the warning message, it's not a medical advice, it's a kind of, like, a,
Deepti: Kind of like, don't just wait for any severe problem here, just you can go ahead and consult the professionals, but it can give you the,
Deepti: health-related healthcare AI, kind of like trying to learn the context from the base model and giving you the context-related answers for your questions.
Deepti: Okay, so…
Deepti: If you are okay, then moving on to the code view, like how we have done. So, this is actually, like,
Deepti: we see we have, the data. It's, the data we have, the non-instruction data, which is actually having the paragraphs and all, like, most of the related to that, related to the general healthcare AI… general healthcare, data.
Deepti: from paragraphs and sentences.
Deepti: And also in the instruction data set, you can see like I have given, it's kind of like the question and answers one, like instructions and response around like 100, yeah, 100 of the instruction data set. And also I have the preference data set where we have given, when we are giving the prompt, which is chosen response and which are not chosen one, like reject
Deepti: response. So you can see here this is all like we have it in the data already and then if you go to so these are the different like how we are trained from base model to instruction and from there to DPO.
Deepti: So, from non-instruction, like, fine-tuning, we can just… it's a basic… all the basic steps we followed here, we are just first
Deepti: Tried to load and pre-process the domain text.
Deepti: And from there, we are actually also loading the base model with Onslaught.
Deepti: So the Llama model, what I have used for this one. And then we are trying to apply the adapters using the LoRa and QLoRa so that we are cleaning up. And also we have the tokenized data set, what we just have opened the data.
Deepti: And then we are, configuring and run the training. So we are training, doing it, so cleaning up and everything. And then, so we are trying to save the adapter, and we get, like, it's a kind of, like, we are testing the model after the non-instruction fine-tuning.
Deepti: So in this way, we are actually done the non-instruction fine tuning here. So we can see after completing the stage one, the model should now complete the healthcare domain sentences more fluently using the domain specific terminology.
Deepti: So we have base model, we gave the non-instruction data, so now we've got the domain-specific data, domain-specific data more fluently. Then we are moving on to the instruction fine-tuning.
Deepti: So, in the instruction fine-tuning, we are actually, whatever the model we got from non-instruction, we have that the model going to be loaded here, and as well as the dataset going to the instruction fine-tuning. So, here also you can see, it's kind of like we are, again, dataset, we are preparing the dataset.
Deepti: and then we are trying to we get all this prompts and everything we have given that and also we are trying to load that model with unsloth and also like the one whatever the load models we again it's a common space thing like you load the data set load the model format the data set and everything and but you are trying to load it with adapters and making sure you're
Deepti: having all the training arguments and training complete. So you can see that, like, we have the loss, the final loss, what are all the things we have.
Deepti: And in the same way here, we are training the model, making it ready for the next model. So after training the model, we're just trying to save it. And we're going to interference, kind of like we're going to save.
Deepti: I mean, we got the model, and we are saving it. That, again, this SFT model goes to input this DPO alignment, one, where we are, again, load the model
Deepti: Get the, use this preference data set as the data, do the basic thing like we're gonna load model data set and train it with the adapters.
Deepti: So, this way, you can actually, like, you can see, and also, kind of, like, I tried to have the reports here, like, whatever I have showed in the PPT, those are the kind of, like, what we have it here. So…
Deepti: Kind of, like, kind of, this is kind of, like, for the,
Deepti: instruction, fine-tuning instruction, but of course, we have to move on to the RAG. The main challenge, what I have actually,
Deepti: faced when I'm actually putting into the health media. Sometimes the model actually like whenever if it keeps running, it is okay. Sometimes it is failing to load because of the launch and the space issues also what I have seen.
Deepti: Any questions or anything you want me to? Okay.
Sunny: Okay, you are done, right?
Deepti: Okay.
Sunny: Okay, great. Yeah, again, a very good, organized, basically demonstration. So, your, code is ready, right, Deepthi? You uploaded it over the GitHub?
Deepti: Yes, I have uploaded it at the GitHub.
Sunny: Okay, okay, that's good. You can basically share in the chat itself so that everyone can go through with it, okay? So, did you take a help of the, basically, AI co-pilots, or you prepared everything by yourself and you took just a minimalistic help from the AI?
Deepti: So I took help of AI kind of like when I'm doing the collab, I was kind of like having the idea on the steps like, okay, we need to load the model, we need to load the data set, get the adopters. So I have kind of like took the help from the step by step kind of like, okay, I need to do this one. So I need to get the code for that one. So in that way, I'm trying to refine my
Deepti: pipeline architecture, it's not that I have done the coding line by line, so I have to make sure that, like, I'm making… getting the concept as well as getting the help of the AI for that step, instead of getting the whole thing all at once.
Sunny: Okay, okay, great. Yeah, again, it's a good strategy. Thank you, thank you, Deepti, for the demonstration. We can give chance to the other folks. Now,
Sunny: Kaushik, Anil, anyone is there, please go ahead.
Anil Venkatrao: Yeah. Hi, Sunny, I can go ahead.
Sunny: Yeah, please.
Anil Venkatrao: Let me share my screen.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay.
Anil Venkatrao: Hope it's visible.
Sunny: Yeah, it is visible.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay. Okay, guys, so, you know, as you know, so…
Anil Venkatrao: Hi, everyone. First, let me introduce myself. I am Anil Venkatrao, and thank you, Sunny, for giving me the opportunity. So, let me begin with my fine-tuning explanation, whatever I have learned from Sunny, and
Anil Venkatrao: whatever I could able to capture. So, let me just, you know, walk you through from the beginning. So, this is the, you know, in my GitHub repo, I created this fine-tuned studio project. So, it has, you know, it's a dynamic project, basically. So.
Anil Venkatrao: Let me run it so that I can give up.
Anil Venkatrao: quick walkthrough in the UI and backend and entire code flow architecture, then what is the problem statement, how exactly I'm, you know, comparing all in one screen, so that you could be able to see the
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, fair enough, it started.
Anil Venkatrao: So, this is my, you know, UI screen, where exactly, you know, we have to first… first thing first we have to do is, you know, select the, you know, project, which… project as in, like, you know, you have to give some name to your project, like, you know, fine-tuning assignment
Anil Venkatrao: on, like, you know, it's a dynamic project, so this particular project I have ran on the one dataset called the HR policy, means HR-related,
Anil Venkatrao: Data set I used for this, and another one, another one, you know, is, since I said, right, it's a dynamic, I use other type of data, customer support assistance also, like, I used another data set. So for that also, I used to, how exactly I'm, you know, using this, I'll just explain you in detail, just please bear with me for 5 minutes.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay? Yeah, so let me just give you the overview of what exactly this UI is doing first, okay? So…
Anil Venkatrao: Here, I'll be, you know, uploading the dataset, respective of, like, you know, CPT means continued pre-training, and the non-instruction fine-tuning, SFT means supervised fine-tuning, and DPO means direct preference optimization. So, in the CPT, basically, you know, what exactly you need is, you know, your dataset. So, that dataset, you basically, you know, upload from your project, wherever you have dataset, you can just, you know.
Anil Venkatrao: from your file directory, you can upload the dataset, and after that, select the model, whatever the model you are using. So, basically, you know, I am using the…
Anil Venkatrao: I'm using the, like, you know, this, 0.5 billion parameter coin, because, you know, why exactly I'm doing here, that you can see in my hardware. So, this is my… my hardware doesn't have, you know, a GPU. I have only CPU, that is 32GB.
Anil Venkatrao: So, keeping in mind that, so I just, you know, using this, like, you know, it, just load, you know, few parameters, a few, dataset quantity only it can accept, so that's why I'm going with the 0.5 million parameter of.
Anil Venkatrao: base model. And here is, like, you know, basically, once you start, like, you know, giving this, as Sunny was giving in the…
Anil Venkatrao: While explaining, he has given this parameterized mass sequence label, how many parameters, it means how many tokens your model process, and batch size, gradient accumulation, max step means epochs.
Anil Venkatrao: So, logging after how many steps log should be. So, all those parameters I have defined here, like, you know, in UI itself, you can give it. So, once you are given, you have, you know, you have data set
Anil Venkatrao: And that data set, you know, will be, you know, showcased here in the drop-down.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, and after that, you have your model, then the type HTS, like, which, like, knows CPD and all you can do, you can start the training. Once you start the training, right, it will, you know, the right side, it will give the logs. See, this, I have already ran it, so you can see the logs.
Anil Venkatrao: This is how it's, you know, running the steps and all. So, this I'm storing because, you know, once I lose the server or anything, I shouldn't, you know, lose my training data or my parameters, so that's why I, you know, kept everything, you know, in a DB. I'm using SQLite DB, so there I'm storing all the data, as you can see right here, I have all the data structure.
Anil Venkatrao: database schemas, and that, you know, if you want to run any of the particular, you can just, you know, run those particular things, so it will show the… all the, you know, your run related. So, for example, now you are… you are having this run ID 7, right? So, this is what we have done, right? So, here you can see.
Anil Venkatrao: what is the project ID, what is the, you know, parameters you're using, so all the detail I'm using, so that I should not lose the data of my
Anil Venkatrao: and of the run case okay so this this line is completed once this is done right so after that you know once it is done I'll again go ahead and upload my instruction fine-tuning so like you know I use the HR data set let's say I have to go to go and upload that data set so how exactly it's segregate is basically JSON PDF PDF for JSON lines I'm taking so in JSON lines if it has instruction
Anil Venkatrao: And, you know, a response. If… if the data set is type is that, that kind is that, then it will pick… it will consider this data set is particularly for the SFT, supervised fine-tuning.
Anil Venkatrao: So that's how it, you know, automatically, you know, my, you know, project will identify that. So it, you know, it just, you know, shows me those related to this. So we can select any data set, whichever you load it.
Anil Venkatrao: And again, same here. Now, the, you know, here the catch point being, right, you don't have to use, you know, this is a default one, I have kept it here. But, you know, you can, you know, give the last time one. So CPT has been completed in the with line, right, so you have
Anil Venkatrao: So, like, as Sunny was saying, right, like, merging your model first, and on top of that, using that continuously for the next SFT and all. And once that is done, you give, you know, specific related to SFT parameter, and start the project.
Anil Venkatrao: So, once this is done, again, you have to, you know, upload your data set for the preference. Preference, you're using prompt, choose, and reject, right? So, based on that kind, it will select the data set kind. So, you just, you know, select that, and particularly, after that, you select the SFT1. So, if you can see here, right? So, the 9 one is… here, it's a fail. So, 9 one is…
Anil Venkatrao: you know, added to the project ID 13, okay? So that's why the 13 is successful here. Like, in Jenkins, build… build ID will be there, right? Something will be failed, but whatever success, you just take that, right? So 9… 9 is nothing but my CPT.
Anil Venkatrao: merge model. That 9, I'm, you know, keeping to the SFT, so the SFT is successful with the 13 project ID.
Anil Venkatrao: misrun ID. And after that, 13, I'm… this data I'm passing to the DPO for continuous, you know, merge model for continuous fine-tuning, okay? So that is all… basically, it's a service ID only, but in a different style, that's all.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, this is how my UI, you know, UI looks like. So, let me just give you an overview of, like, you know, as I said, I have processed for HR policy. I've taken on a simple company called Recap Capital Private Limited. Their data, I did the fine-tuning.
Anil Venkatrao: And another, our data set, you know, so for, you know, company is, customer assistance for Engston State University customer assistance. So different, it's a dynamic project. You can give any model, you can give any data set, it will just accept it and, you know, give all the data and store in the database, so that, you know, you can
Anil Venkatrao: use it anytime. Even though your server crashes and all, you just restart the server, and you can, you know, be there wherever you halted, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: That's how it is. So I'm just currently showing you for the… this particular data set, HR policy data set, okay? So here I have, you know, a compare model, so I'll just, you know,
Anil Venkatrao: Oh, it's…
Bhargav A: Okay, I'll…
Anil Venkatrao: Do this.
Anil Venkatrao: Oh, sorry, so this Engston State University one I'm giving, so what, so the question I will be asking, like, purpose of customer service assistance occupation. So this is the question I'll be asking to our,
Anil Venkatrao: AI model. So, like, for… like, you know, this is the train, and then evaluate, I have given this one. So, code walkthrough, I'll give you guys, so just bear with me. So, this is for evaluate, and this is for Hugging Face. So, whatever you've done, right? So, with the… like, which
Anil Venkatrao: your continuous pre-training or supervised fine-tuning or DPU whatever you complete so merge model will be there available with the placeholder I'll be telling you how exactly where and all it will be stored so if you can see here it will be available in certain so I am showing you the nine one right so nine if you can see as Sunny was showing right adapter one and merge one so merge all the data is there so these you have to you know just give this run ID so run
Anil Venkatrao: Or an ID will be having all the,
Anil Venkatrao: this run ID you can give, like, here, you can give 9, and you can give repo ID, whatever, in your Hugging Face, like, let's say, you know, Anil, MP, some, like, whatever model you want to, like, you know, give, you can just give, like, DPO,
Anil Venkatrao: align something you can give here, okay? So the repo ID. And after that, Hugging Face write token. Once you do the publish, it automatically does behind the scene. Basically, code does it. I'll just walk you through that code as well, but this is how it's published, okay? So that also I can show you if you want, but presently, let me show you how exactly this evaluation is happening, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: Please let me know, guys, if I'm going fast, or if you're not, you know, following with me.
Anil Venkatrao: But let me just… There's the question, then after.
Sunny: Yeah, no, the speed is good, Venkat. Please go in your speed only, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: This is Anil Sami. Yeah, thank you very
Anil Venkatrao: So I, I'll be selecting, like, you know, all the, you know, models. So this is the base model. Then if you can see here, right, like, 9, the run ID 9 is CPT. So…
Anil Venkatrao: And after that, you know, SFT. SFT, like, 9… 9 merge model is, continued with the SFT, so the…
Anil Venkatrao: But.
Anil Venkatrao: That run ID is 13. After that, you know, one more after that, you know, the 14 is for DPO.
Anil Venkatrao: So, this is all the comparison I'm doing in the UI, rather than, you know, keeping it in a PPT or in a document. So, just, you know, through real-time experience, I'm explaining you what, you know, for this, you know, customer assistance of this, Youngstown State University, okay? I'm just running you now.
Sunny: So, Anil, you created this, UI using what, HTML or any other framework?
Anil Venkatrao: No, like, you know, this, you know, the code walkthrough till that, you know, loads, I'll just give you the code walkthrough first, you know, spec-driven development, right, Sunny? So, you're much aware… you are much more aware than me. So, that's what we are doing. I have done it. So, if you can see here, right, we have a preview of my architecture, so…
Anil Venkatrao: So, basically, you know, first, that, whatever this is, whatever your screen you're seeing, right, index.html, the, you know, what…
Anil Venkatrao: whenever which button you click, what should happen, and also app.js is for, you know, basically which all of the project and data set, how you should load. So, style is basically styling of my UI, and after that, you know, the project.py, the Python script, so…
Anil Venkatrao: From that, you know, whenever I run, I will just give it this service.pi, you know, runs where exactly, you know, it gets all the, you know, what are the services running. So what are the parameter I configure, what is the configuration for path storing and all those details. So job queues like, you know, queued, complete and failed status, those will be here.
Anil Venkatrao: And after that, you know, like, managing with the registry and the contracts of the, basically, CPTO, what it has to do, SFT and DPO, those other details will be here.
Anil Venkatrao: And after that, here, if you can see the contacts of each, each one. So, you know, basically, you know, interface-based, implementations. So, registry, you know, like, you know, registry, your,
Anil Venkatrao: registry of all the services, and after that, you know, with Singleton, the dependency, one container I'm giving, so based on that, it just picks up the, whatever the current, application it's serving. So you can now, like, you know, parallelly, this, this thing has generated me the value. So if you can see, this is the base model, and this is CPT.
Anil Venkatrao: CPT is nothing but run here, right? So it's CPT here.
Anil Venkatrao: So, 9-1, and here the 13 means SFT, and the 14th one is DPO.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay.
Anil Venkatrao: Was giving me a file, not sure now exactly what happened.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, so the, you know, the primary one, if you can see red base model, so here, you know, it gives any, you know, like, it's giving me just randomly any HR policy related, not customer assistance related, random answer it's giving me, if you can see, the primary purpose of the customer service assistance is
Anil Venkatrao: customer assistance with any question or concern, like, you know, general answer it's giving, that model it's giving, so which is not, you know, specific to our content.
Anil Venkatrao: Then, here, if you can see, right, the primary purpose of customer service is to provide assistance, information, process transaction for internal or external customers. So, if you can see it, you know, kind of, you know.
Anil Venkatrao: It kind of, you know, matches with our answer, if you can see here, right? So, three occupations, like, you know, assistance we are giving, information we are giving, and processing the transaction, internal or external customers. So, that with those, how exactly you are getting through the email, complaint, or whatever, we are just, you know, validating those details. So, that kind of answer my CPT is giving is non-instruction fine-tuning is giving it.
Anil Venkatrao: And after that, if you can see here, right, so there, this, SFT also giving me the, you know, exactly precise data, whatever I needed.
Anil Venkatrao: This was also working fine, not sure, like, you know, just, just now I started server in front of you, right? Might be, might be, you know, just some issues might have happened here, but, you know, this is what, this was working fine. I'll just, you know, run for other, you know, data set, right? At that time, we can just, you know, compare it, okay? This is for one data set, which is
Anil Venkatrao: customer assistant data set for, you know, state, university-related, any, you know, customer assistance for that particular data set. So I'll just, as I said, right, this is the customer support assistance. I'll just, you know, pick it up, other one that is nothing but HR-related.
Anil Venkatrao: HR-related one. Here, also, if you can see, right, guys, so here, also, I have done for, like, you know, once I select a project, right, specific to that run ID, it will showcase to me, because, you know, here, if you see, earlier, I used here 9…
Anil Venkatrao: 9, 13, and 14 IOUs, but here, if you can see, right, for this, HR-related, once I change the data set, this is for HR-related, not customer assistance. So then, I have selected the particular project, so that project, when I select the run IDs, 6, 7, and 8, which is CPT, SFT, and DPO, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So, this is how it's, you know, using it. Now, like, you know, I'll just, you know, you can see the, you know, logs here for all the SFT and all, like, what is the final, you know, 1.16. So, it started all the way from the 3 and something, and the loss has reduced to all the way to 1.16 during my 64th run, 64th epoch.
Anil Venkatrao: So, this is for DPA also, same thing, you know, it, it kind of did some, close to, you know, overfitting the scenario it came for it. Okay, so this, again, I'm evaluating, so I have to select the respective run ID, so let me just select the run ID. This is for…
Anil Venkatrao: CPT and is for.
Anil Venkatrao: SFT, and this is for one ID, 8 is for.
Anil Venkatrao: 6, 7, 8. Yeah, 6, 7, 8. So, this is for, you know, the CPT run, and this is for SFT run, and this is for DPU run, okay? I'll just, you know, change the HR assistance related, any question I'll pick, so… not to waste any time, I kept all the data here to us, to our…
Anil Venkatrao: compare your models, so I'll just, you know, compare the answer, I'll say. It just generates all those answers here.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, meantime, it generates, it just takes time, because it's running on CPU, so I've also configured in such a dynamic way that you can, you know, based on the hardware, it picks up, like, you know, I'm using CPU, so it picks the CPU and runs the transformer behind the scene. If you can see, right, backward, which thing it
Anil Venkatrao: either Transformer or Unsloth. So, Unsloth only runs if you have, you know, CUDA-related or
Anil Venkatrao: an NVIDIA graphics card, which Sony system has it. If he runs this project in his system, definitely it shows here as a CUDA.
Anil Venkatrao: And, you know, whatever the float precision it has, it shows that one, whichever, you know, up to the max it's available in your system, it shows those details over there.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, so it's still generating, let it generate. So, I'll just walk you through the code here. So, if you can see, right, as I was saying, the initial phase being our, you know, UI, where exactly our project will be loaded.
Anil Venkatrao: So, here, if you can see, right, in the initialized one, the… I'm loading the device-related information trainer, like, information kinds, what kind of data set, whether it is SFT and all those…
Anil Venkatrao: details I'm loading, and index, I'll be definitely, you know, you know, once I press button, what should happen? If I press, you know, continue, like, you know, dataset button or parameter button, what should happen? So all those details will be there in this, index one.
Anil Venkatrao: in this device, man, button, in this division column, and here, style is basically, you know, the styling over, like, you know, center, bottom, and right, what should be the content should be there, that styling is there.
Anil Venkatrao: And the, you know, starting point will be our, you know, projects.pi. So here I can see that fast API using, I just use the route for projects and, you know, getting the project, getting the device information, so all the detail I'll be getting here.
Anil Venkatrao: So, and after that, if you are seeing, right, so it will call the API-related information, so…
Anil Venkatrao: Huh, device, so you are saying, right, so device-related information, so whatever the device information you have, so it, you know, picks based on the device information, like, basically, if you have, you know, the CPU, or the only device which has only CPU, so it picks the CPU, or else if you have CUDA available, then, you know, it picks up the, your CUDA in the UI, and if you have the, you know, like, MPS, this is for Apple systems, and this is for, you know.
Anil Venkatrao: or… CPO at the end, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So that's how we know we have done it here. And artifactory storage, like you can see right in front of you, only I started the server, but still all my data is available. This is how I'm maintaining it. I'm writing all the details into the DB, okay? With using this persistence package, I am keeping all this DB.py, like whatever has to happen.
Anil Venkatrao: And in the model, like, you know, which, like, you know, project, table, whatever the IDM is, or whatever the, you know, I have rows, so those rows which, which, which, you know, particular, you know.
Anil Venkatrao: class, and what is the valued speaking and mapping, so all those data set, RAN, and all this, you know, the related information will be here, if you can see in the DB, right? So here.
Anil Venkatrao: I will show the, my DBs and these things. So, here you can see artifact, dataset, evaluation result, and project, runs. So, runs is, you know, all the runs, information, right? Till now, whatever I have run. So, those, runs-related information, I, I will not lose it, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So this is how my, events are, like, you know
Anil Venkatrao: defined here, like, if I see 13 one, right? See, it shows the kind of SFT. For 13, it's SFT, and what is the, you know, parameter I use, what time I have ran it, so those details, you can see it over here, like, what is the…
Anil Venkatrao: I know what parameters I use. So, this is how I did. So, if I see… if you see other also, you can see it, like, how… like, right now, I ran the evaluation, right? So, what is the, like, evaluation result also? I'm… I'll be storing it here inside this.
Anil Venkatrao: see the, you know, evaluation, whatever I have ran recently, right? So that, that, evaluation also will be, you know, storing here. So if you can see what is the, question I have, you know, added to that, and I'll… I have informed that over there.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay? And, so…
Anil Venkatrao: this is how it runs, and ultimately, you know, Hugging Face related in the UI you are seeing, right? So, backend side, it is using the token, and, you know, what are all the repos I have, you know, created, mispublished related, what are all the information I have needed, so repo ID, token, adapter, merge, so those details I'll be…
Anil Venkatrao: I'm keeping, and I'm using the token, whatever you will be given there, and the API…
Anil Venkatrao: Based on that, I'll be creating the report, pushing my, details to the Hugging Face. That is how I'm doing it.
Anil Venkatrao: And if you can see here in the below, so this is related to the job you are seeing, right? Completed, failed, so those related information, job queue is there.
Anil Venkatrao: And after that, you know, the final one, whatever the DB you are seeing, right? So the DB-related info.
Anil Venkatrao: It is speaking from the studio.db. So this is the file I opened over there. So schema table related information. This is the file it's holding those data. And as Sunny was saying, right, this adapter, how exactly this merge one, it's like, you know, I'm storing it here by using persistence one, right?
Anil Venkatrao: as I was showing, right, how exactly this, direct writing I'm doing, so that… that detail is in front.
Anil Venkatrao: That information is, you know, contained here. So I want to show you the common one, like, you know, the parameter where I'm using the common parameter and, you know, model-specific parameter that I want to, you know, specifically see. This is the common parameter being, like, all the
Anil Venkatrao: you know, parameters, CPT, and, you know, SFT, and DPO, whatever the parameter, common parameters are there, I am just, you know, keeping it over here. And the specific related, you know, whatever the, you have, you know, CPT related, or, you know, DPO related, those, related will be there, so those are here.
Anil Venkatrao: you know, it picks up from here, like, you know, CPT-related parameter only here, and, you know, SFT-related parameter here, what all the details I need to pass, so those are all the details are over here.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay? And, this api.pi, like, you know, whenever your project create and run create, you do, do, so those, it will, you know, by using this, facade, factory design, this facade, design pattern, it just, you know, creates for you.
Anil Venkatrao: As I was explaining the architecture of this one. And, you know, like, you know, this, CPT, how exactly this, trainer preparing register, how exactly we are doing, so that register pattern, I'm using it here.
Anil Venkatrao: This is how I'm using it, like, again, like, as I was, as I was explaining. And, this project.rml will hold all your, you know, like, requirement.txt was he's using in the class, right? The same package detail, I'll be adding it here, so you will think you can do it in your project once you know.
Anil Venkatrao: and just, you know, use my project in your, system, you can just, do. It will automatically download all those, dependency for in your, I mean, this mod in your system.
Anil Venkatrao: So, this is the code walkthrough of this one, and let me just go, and it might have generated… no, see, it's generated, like, I have just asked for HR-related, what is the primary purpose of the HR policies at Rickhelp Capital Private Limited, the company.
Anil Venkatrao: So, general thing I ask. So, if you see here, right, in the model one, you know, given me all this, you know, information, like, you know.
Anil Venkatrao: over the period, it has, you know, learned, but, you know, not giving any specific related information in this, if you can see here, right? If you read out this one information, right? It's just giving me all the, you know, generic, whatever the other company policies are, the same it is, you know, giving me there. But here, if you can see, right,
Anil Venkatrao: company's values, this, you know, HR policy of flexible, inclusive culture, so the, you know, the CPT has given me whatever the information I have, you know, given in this particular form, the, you know, it's given me that one, and the instruction on the…
Anil Venkatrao: you know, for, like, an overall, like, what all the HR policy does, hiring, firing, and training them, and managing the workforce. So this is the, you know, instruction fine-tuning answer. And DPO1, the chosen one, being this one, the primary objective is to provide clear guidelines and, you know, standard for managing human resource.
Anil Venkatrao: Aiming to enhance productivity, consistency, and compliance of the organization. So this is how the DPA has chosen the answer and given to me.
Anil Venkatrao: So, this is my overall, you know, project, guys, so…
Anil Venkatrao: Yeah, Sunny, I am pretty much done with my explanation.
Anil Venkatrao: So, yeah.
Anil Venkatrao: If any comment, please.
Sunny: Yeah, so that's a really great,
Sunny: Anil, you did a good job, actually. So, Anil, there are some questions in the chat. Can you meanwhile answer those questions?
Anil Venkatrao: Sure.
Anil Venkatrao: Which question I should, you know, focus now?
Anil Venkatrao: Huh, to understand this, right, so you can, you know, first, you know, like, you know, I also, you know, did, like, whatever the knowledge I have, like, you know, my…
Anil Venkatrao: you know, industry standard knowledge, or whatever the development knowledge I used it. So, basically, I was from Java, and then Python also, over the period, I learned it, and you can… the starting point being, right, you can just come here in the architecture.md, and in the… you… you can, you know, install your,
Anil Venkatrao: you know, this, one… this plugin will come… come up, guys. So, you just use a marathon preview, something, right? So, this plugin you install, so it will give the… your, you know, mermaid, architecture, then ERD, entity relationship diagram, it will give. So, how exactly it's working. So, it's self-explanatory, you can just go through this one, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: Here, everything is available for you. Just don't open this, you know, directly. If you directly open it, it gives, like, this, it will not give any information to you. So, install that particular plugin, then go, go in the preview model, preview mode, okay? In the preview mode, if you go, it will exp… it is, you know, self-explanatory, like, how exactly flow is happening, like, you know, which is the class it's using.
Anil Venkatrao: So, if you can see, right from here, first time, I'm coming from UI, project.pi is the first class, then I'm running the services.
Anil Venkatrao: And service also calling this job queue, like, you know, to know the status. And manager is, you know, how exactly, you know, what are the devices you are managing, and those details. So here, you can see, trainers, what are the trainers you are using, and, you know, those, whether your backend you're using based on your device configuration, whether you're using transformer, onslaught.
Anil Venkatrao: this, you know, architecture delayed, and, like, you know, contact here. Basically, you know, any project you'll be, you know, working, you'll be having, right, interfaces, you know
Anil Venkatrao: And, you know, registry, you can just leave it if you are not understanding, but, you know, this should be basic, you know, interfaces and abstract classes will be basic, right? So registry and event, it will be, you know, a bit, you know, difficult if you're a beginner in development and all. It's a design pattern, again, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So, all this detail will be, you know, holding over in this, you know, data-related will be, like, whatever the data set I'm uploading in the URL, so those will be holding here, you know, these,
Anil Venkatrao: my instruction fine-tuning. There's two datasets I work with. One is HR policy dataset, other is the customer support. So, two datasets. You can use an infinite number of datasets, whatever you want. It'll keep on just storing in your database, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So that's how, you know, data-related information it will hold. App is like, you know, like, it's a base, you know, folder. Like, inside that app, only API-related information means some backend, what all the, you know, transformer, onslaught I'm using, like, you know, these, you know, package core info. You go one by one, okay? If you want, I'll just, you know, I can give one more class if Sunny avoids me, but, you know, in this,
Anil Venkatrao: Particularly, whatever the time window I have been given, I cannot, you know, walk you through all the, you know, classes
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, even, you know, you know, to be honest, whatever, whatever, you know, AI help I have taken, on top of that AI help only, I did, you know, what all the work I could able to do, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So that's the same only, okay? And this, as Sunny was explaining, no one develops from scratch nowadays. It's just your self-knowledge plus AI development. That's how I also did it, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So here, if you can see, all the dependencies, related ones. So these, all the dependencies, and a kind of singleton one. So one container.
Anil Venkatrao: will be, I'll be having, so this container only will be doing all the, you know, which, whenever I need to call, it calls the, you know, container.eventbus, container.jobQueue, what is the status of jobQueue, and what is the, you know, whether you have Torch, means for graphics card, if you have Torch, it will use, and if you have, you know.
Anil Venkatrao: project repository-related data set, whatever the repository you're in. So, this rep… through this repository, again, you'll be having your respective development, right? So, those… again, it calls the method. So, you just… you have to go through complete, one-by-one line-wise, if you want to see, and debug it, if you're possible, but…
Anil Venkatrao: you know, the base point, if you can keep it, this architecture, whatever the preview I give you, right? This, this you can, you know, give the Azure base point here. The entities means, tables.
Anil Venkatrao: schemas, whatever I used, you can, you know, able to see it here inside this, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: So, that… that… That's all I can get, so…
Sunny: Great, great, Daniel. It's a very excellent work. I really like that you went beyond the assignment requirement, actually. Okay, so instead of just creating this notebook-based solution.
Sunny: You build an end-to-end, fine-tuning platform, right?
Sunny: I had seen that Llama factory, actually, I was using that, and it is a similar kind of solution, basically, you build, right, with a clean architecture, modular design, okay, and even with the live comparison between the pre-trained model, SFTDPA model, and all. It's a very, like, strong engineering thinking. That's great, Anil.
Anil Venkatrao: Yeah, yeah. You know, as I was saying, right, I have, you know, 10 years of development experience, so basically, we know how things we need to develop.
Sunny: Correct, correct.
Anil Venkatrao: Mr. No.
Sunny: For building, I think also, like, you need the experience, correct? Even though AI is doing work for you, but again, you need that thinking process, thought process, right?
Anil Venkatrao: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sunny: Great, Anil, everyone is appreciating, so, yeah, you can share your LinkedIn as well, so that everyone can connect with you, and, even you can share your, updated code also, okay?
Anil Venkatrao: Sure, it's already available, let me just, you know, just give me one minute, so you can see, right, if anyone wants to, you know, use my project, right, you know, directly, you can, you know, I'm sharing it in the chat, so I've just explained, you know, how exactly you can, you know, anyone can learn it, it's completely dynamic, okay, you don't have to go through each and every one, whatever thing you want to do, you can.
Anil Venkatrao: So this is the one I'll just walk through how exactly you just, you know, you know, clone my, you know, this rep
Anil Venkatrao: just, you know, inside this one, this particular, fine-tuned studio is there, right? So just, you know, point your, point your project to that one, and just, you know, do EVSync first, so that, you know, it will sync all your, from project.toml, it will sync all your, you know, models. So once that is done, right, so let me just minimize everything, so…
Anil Venkatrao: inside this one, right? The project.toml will sync all this, you know, whatever the, whatever the module you needed, and after that, you know, once that is done, you know, you do whatever the command I have ran here, right? So, you know, you will run fine-tuned studio, so run this particular project. Once you're done, the server will start with the.
Anil Venkatrao: You know, let me just give you the placeholder for this one, so… Configuration… There.
Anil Venkatrao: config.py, if you can see here, right, so these are, you know, local, local, or this is my host, this is my port, and this is, you know, property, you know, what is the, you know, parent, parent folder being, like, you know, app, app is the parent, so after that, you know, you can see, right, there's nothing, right, data directory.
Anil Venkatrao: and runs directory, and, you know, I have DB path, and, you know, okay, so…
Anil Venkatrao: This all information I'm holding up here, so then this is how, you know, this configuration is given.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, now if you go inside, if you see, right, so you can also see where exactly, your, particular project is getting the continued, pre-continued when you do, right, how exactly it's work and all, you can see it, you know, just try to know F12 you do.
Anil Venkatrao: And you just click on that particular thing, like, you know, you know, right? So, development on F12.
Anil Venkatrao: If you do here, right, so…
Anil Venkatrao: Just click on this one, you can go whichever project you want to go, okay? Where exactly that is located, how exactly it's calling, and all, you can just…
Anil Venkatrao: development, this window will be there, right? For you, you can just, you know, navigate through that architecture, and then navigate through this develop…
Anil Venkatrao: developer, that developer window will be available, right? You can just navigate and, you know, go to any code from starting to end. However, your co-pilot, I use the… as I was saying earlier, I have company… this is my company laptop, and I have company's co-pilot, premium co-pilot.
Anil Venkatrao: So, you know, with help of ITData, and you can, you know, ask any particular, you know, package and or class, if you're not understanding, ask Copilot, okay? It will help you. That's all.
Anil Venkatrao: what more I can say, and that's what, like, you know, everything is available inside the source fine-tuned studio, right? Inside this, all this, as I was explaining, these are all the details available over here, okay? You can just make use of this one, yeah.
Sunny: Thank you, thank you, Anil. Thank you very much for the demonstration, and yeah, thank you.
Anil Venkatrao: Okay, thank you.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Okay, Anil is done. Akashic, if you're there, then please go.
Kaushik Banerjee: Yeah, I'm there, I'm there. Yeah.
Kaushik Banerjee: It has been a good experience of seeing different people, seeing different products and their concepts.
Kaushik Banerjee: It was a nice experience.
Kaushik Banerjee: And, it was a nice session, thanks for that.
Kaushik Banerjee: Second thing is that my objective of doing this project was to check what I've learned.
Kaushik Banerjee: And to migrate my existing product that I am going on to this platform. So that was, so initially I did this entire project on my, office lab and office lab, office desktop.
Kaushik Banerjee: So that I know that the configuration is more or less required if I go ahead with my migrating my existing products.
Kaushik Banerjee: So, so the code or the demonstration that I'm going to show will not be that very high grade, but anything, the objective was to just stick to what I was, requested. I mean, what was instructed, and I delivered, tried to deliver. We were thinking of the UI and all those parts.
Kaushik Banerjee: So how can I share my screen? Just let me see, I'll share my screen, let me know if it is visible.
Kaushik Banerjee: Hmm.
Kaushik Banerjee: Is it visible?
Sunny: Yeah, it is visible.
Kaushik Banerjee: Okay, I'll just start with a simple presentation first.
Kaushik Banerjee: So that'll give… I'll try to… I'll try to explain what I
Kaushik Banerjee: Then I'll go into the GitHub, where you can see, what I've loaded, and directly onto my development platform, where I actually, set up the environment and created it.
Kaushik Banerjee: So, this is… let me just minimize this first.
Kaushik Banerjee: And I think this is bothering me a lot.
Kaushik Banerjee: So, this is my GitHub interface, which I'll go, when I finish with this presentation.
Kaushik Banerjee: So this is the entire pipeline, which I thought, fits the requirement of the project. So I started with base LLM, which is QN, QN2.5, 1.58 instruct. I think, let me see if I can maximize this a bit.
Kaushik Banerjee: Let me know if it is visible now, or let me do something.
Kaushik Banerjee: Things are… I might have messed up a bit, just don't.
Kaushik Banerjee: Okay, so next thing is that, so it has the three stages, obviously. It started with pre-trained knowledge. I used a base, base LLM for that, broad language understanding. So, as I had a very limited, resources, so I went there with the one.
Kaushik Banerjee: And the stage one, what I did is the raw IT helpers. This is where I told what are the technologies. I chose actually the IT platform, but that is what I know best. I don't have much idea of the HR and all those steps, but as I am from the development background, so I chose IT.
Kaushik Banerjee: So what I did, first, then this stage one, as it requires, is the… is to tell the model that these are the technical terms that we are going to use as part of the model. So don't say… let's be very clear, I didn't train it from the perspective of giving a very good model, but train it from the perspective
Kaushik Banerjee: Presenting that what it could be done.
Kaushik Banerjee: So, the stage one, it is a raw IT helpdesk. I'll come to those, what are those inputs I created. So, here it created a learned domain vocabulary and terminology, capture patterns from IT helpdesk. So, it gives a complete idea, ki, how my IT domain
Kaushik Banerjee: functions, actually. I mean, the terminologies and what are needed. Then comes the instruction fine-tuning, where I give you the possible questions and possible answers. Here it
Kaushik Banerjee: it trained in that way. And finally, in the stage 3, where is the direct preparation of reference optimization, I got what not to say, what to reject. So that's how this total model evolved, and finally, I created an inference pipeline through which I can at least run and check that the model is running. Nothing more than that. I don't have a UI, I don't have anything else.
Kaushik Banerjee: And so… Oh.
Kaushik Banerjee: So, this is the technology stack that I've used. Basically, I've used Python 3.1
Kaushik Banerjee: Pytorch, Hybrid Quest Transformers, TRL, PFT, Unslock, QLoRa, CUDA, and my, I have a GPU, so it is A5500, and obviously I used VS Code and included, as it was deliverable, was Jupyter Notebook, so I kept it in a Jupyter Notebook-style presentation.
Kaushik Banerjee: So, this is the stage one, what I did, as I said, basically.
Kaushik Banerjee: The objective was to adapt this model to the IT helpdesk domain by exposing a domain-specific technique. When I say domain-specific, I mean the IT domain. Very specific terms that we're going to use in the demos. So, in the input, I gave him as a raw helpdesk documentation. On the output, I created the Stage 1 Loader Adapter. The model successfully learned the technology and its support language. Evaluation metrics showed that a reduction in validation
Kaushik Banerjee: I'll showcase those particular, when I go to the court.
Kaushik Banerjee: Next thing that comes is the objective as the stage 2. Here, I give you various sequences, then this is the question, this is the possible answer. So that particular state was, provided to him. Teach the adapter so that
Kaushik Banerjee: First, we teach the adapted model to answer structured IT support questions. Here, my input is an instruction dataset consisting of instruction and expected response. Results the model learns generate significantly more structured and useful responses. Evaluation loss decreased substantially. Perplexity improved dramatically.
Kaushik Banerjee: The next one, finally, the stage three. Here are improved answer quality. That is what to reject. I teach that particular model along with the possible answers in the stage three.
Kaushik Banerjee: Lastly, this is the final inference pylon, that is the priority order stage. If we're running, I go through the stage 3, stage 2, stage 1, and the best model. This is the
Kaushik Banerjee: The challenges, I just… keeping some challenges what I faced, as basically the VS Code was passing.
Kaushik Banerjee: And the Jupyter kernel terminated because I never use Jupyter terminal in my setup. So that was a challenge in that way. So I rebuilt the Python environment, verified the CUDA compatibility, tested unsort independently, validated kernel operations before node revision. And this is all I do so that I can start the process.
Kaushik Banerjee: Next is the next challenge that I've got is the unsloth compatibility. When I'm running it on Linux, I was facing answers. I need to first correlate which particular answer is suitable for my particular disk because ultimately when I go into the production scenario, I need to understand which answer is better. I was a newcomer in this way. So resolutions verified the package versions used compatible releases from confirmed GPU utilization before training.
Kaushik Banerjee: Challenge 3, GPU memory, large language models, GPU resolution, projector, ICP2Q loader, 4-bit quantization, gradient checkpoints, parameter evolution, load adapters. Actually, this reduces the memory consumption sufficient that can be handled by RTX A550.
Kaushik Banerjee: Mmhm
Kaushik Banerjee: The next is the Linux environment. The Linux environment required careful dependency, where there is a GCC+, and all those C++ libraries need to be present, so we should be, again, compatible with the environment that I'm working.
Kaushik Banerjee: Last one on the list, not going much, is the deliverables finally include is the Stage 1 notebook, Stage 2 notebook, Stage 3 notebook, trading reports, evaluation reports, inference application, GitHub repository, and documentation.
Kaushik Banerjee: Now, I'll, move on to, the GitHub part.
Kaushik Banerjee: This is my GitHub repository that I've created, and it's available if you want. And here is the total structure that it runs. There are the configurations, data, logs, notebooks. You can go inside, all the files are maintained in that way only.
Kaushik Banerjee: data maintained in that way. This is a 3 set of data I have used.
Kaushik Banerjee: Now, I would say that, as I was working on a computer,
Kaushik Banerjee: Related to my, office, so I had created
Kaushik Banerjee: my, this data set on certain, AI generation models. So it's not, it's the synthetic data that I worked on.
Kaushik Banerjee: Next come the logs. Everything was the log that went at stage 1, what is the training log, what is the stage 2 logs, all are being maintained out here.
Kaushik Banerjee: In the notebook site, I have kept this, three, the other four, three notebook and one Python file, and this is, this third, fourth Python file is not that much required, it's just for testing it, but
Kaushik Banerjee: This comes, this I'll go, showcase this particular code onto the platform.
Kaushik Banerjee: Outputs. These are the outputs that I mentioned. And each stage, the adapters that is being generated is being kept out here with a definite description on it.
Kaushik Banerjee: I go to the source. This is where the inference lies. I just, mistakenly uploaded an,
Kaushik Banerjee: I mean, a raw one. So don't refer to this inference old if you are at all using like this. It will be the inference pi. So this is all about the Github structure.
Kaushik Banerjee: Here, you can identify that
Kaushik Banerjee: This is the architecture that I've followed. Stage one, continuous pre-training. Stage two, supervised rendering. Stage three, technologies I've already said. Best model is unsolved QAN 2.5 stroke.
Kaushik Banerjee: Fine tuning stage one continued and this is the sample I have kept as was requested that as stage one the baseline loss was 3.5401 final loss was 2.847 perplexity was this.
Kaushik Banerjee: Stage 2.
Kaushik Banerjee: It is, baseline loss is 4.1263, final loss is 1.1394, perplexity is 63.95. Finally, in the Stage 3, I got a DQ loss of, 0.1543, 0.131.
Kaushik Banerjee: And preference accuracy is 100%. But at no point, this is very profitable, that's what I… every time I say, because the very small data, it's only the perspective of presenting the concept that was required… that was instructed, so I developed it.
Kaushik Banerjee: Now, I'll go to my, office terminals, and that will give you some idea of… this is where I developed and tested.
Kaushik Banerjee: And these are the notebooks, obviously out there. The same notebooks are there. There's not much available. I kept this as a presentation, so as a proof that
Kaushik Banerjee: These things were run. This is the… let's start with the non-instruction part.
Kaushik Banerjee: So this is how it went on. It went to the baseline level. So let me go to the top of this.
Kaushik Banerjee: So, basically, these are the stages.
Kaushik Banerjee: That first I created the paths.
Kaushik Banerjee: loaded the modules, tested the GPUs, then loaded and validated the raw domain corpus, Then went out with the…
Kaushik Banerjee: unslowed import, that is very much important for us for this. I'm not explaining this code because this is… I think everyone who have developed this model is similar. Mine is the very simplest one because I just wanted to test the model.
Kaushik Banerjee: And the next thing is that the base model goes on, and then comes the training part.
Kaushik Banerjee: This is how it happens in that way. I'll come to the baseline evaluation, train stage one.
Kaushik Banerjee: This is all the training that I did.
Kaushik Banerjee: It ended out with a training loss of 2.91684.
Kaushik Banerjee: And evaluate after this. Sorry, evaluate after stage and these steps are there. Similar things are there in instruction fine tuning. Just let me this one.
Kaushik Banerjee: It's all the same when I'm just prepared, and at the top, it's all the same in the preparation, and this is where I trained the Stage 2. This was the validation, and the training loss is 1.8325.
Kaushik Banerjee: And, next one is the DPO, that is this one.
Kaushik Banerjee: Here, the training loss is basically, 0.0, so the graduality improved.
Kaushik Banerjee: And, I have run certain inferences from this using the inference that I've kept out here, that this is the…
Kaushik Banerjee: Inference.py.
Kaushik Banerjee: This is where I've, created the how the different things, how to run the stage 3, stage 1, stage 2. This code is out here.
Kaushik Banerjee: And finally, also the interface, because I've been, I've tested it directly on Linux terminal. So let me go to the terminal first. So this is where I was actually testing it.
Kaushik Banerjee: So this is how, I'm in, I've listed out.
Kaushik Banerjee: If you want to run me, I can run. Otherwise, I think, this enough shows that this particular thing is running, and it's giving the output, that's all.
Kaushik Banerjee: Okay.
Kaushik Banerjee: I think I'm done with it.
Kaushik Banerjee: If any queries or questions, you can come out.
Sunny: Okay, thank you, Kaushik. Now guys, if you have any sort of a query, you can write in the chat, okay? Kaushik will reply.
Sunny: So again, Kaushik, good presentation, it's a very structured one. You can share the code and all everything in the chat itself, okay?
Sunny: I added your name, okay.
Sunny: So let's, give chance to the another one, if for.
Sunny: Equal, are you there? Smith Metro?
Sunny: Yeah, if you are there, then please go ahead, or you can share the screen.
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay. Thank you, Sunny, for this. Excellent.
Ekwoge Blaise: Really, yeah, it's… Rochette said to to see the implementation of different different people.
Ekwoge Blaise: So my objective was to create a… sorry, there's a little bit of rain where I am presently, so I hope that you can get me clearly.
Sunny: Yeah, it is, yeah, it is visible, clearly. You can go ahead, Iko.
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay, so my objective was to be able to train a
Ekwoge Blaise: a model from start to end any kind of model from any kind of domain, but to be able to meet up with the objective of the assignment. I 1st of all went on to create
Ekwoge Blaise: for one domain, that is, for the health, the health domain, where I was able to extract data from ChatGPT. Basically, when I'm going to train a new model, I'll explain all of those. But for a start, I already trained
Ekwoge Blaise: this particular model for a health model. But of course my implementation makes use of any kind of domain, as I'm going to illustrate shortly. So I'm going to go to test with what I have already done. Presently I'm using the gradle application.
Ekwoge Blaise: For Google Collabs, so I will not have many kind of, testing to do.
Ekwoge Blaise: And the training may take some time, so I may skip over some of those, but of course I'm going to illustrate them. So for now I'm going to go with the last model that I trained, the DPO model.
Ekwoge Blaise: when you go ahead with it, you load it. So yeah, it has been loaded successfully. I did that just before, because it takes some time to load from the hogging phase.
Ekwoge Blaise: And… After loading the model.
Ekwoge Blaise: you. You can ask questions, whatever questions. This is about health. For example, I've just asked a question. Now, what's the 1st line of treatment for type 2 diabetes, and why it'll give you an answer. There are different kind of questions that you can ask. I have some examples of questions down here.
Ekwoge Blaise: For example, let me say I choose what are the warning signs of heart attack and what should you do, and this is a question, I can just ask the question, and this is going to be loaded, just give it a little bit of time.
Ekwoge Blaise: So this presently is running from a model in the from the hogging phase. So I'll have my my response here. Of course there's always this safety cabbage that is added to make sure that to to die. Since this AI generated responses.
Ekwoge Blaise: And…
Ekwoge Blaise: For this particular stage, I cannot, I can't, I can't equally compare the results from the team, from the 3 different
Ekwoge Blaise: Si, bless him laporte.
Ekwoge Blaise: Terminal code, terminal
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay, sorry about that. Of course you can also compare the results. The same question. You can ask the same question like this question I can ask.
Ekwoge Blaise: and I can compare the results for the different, the different stages, whether it's for the base model, for the supervised fine tuning, or the Tpo.
Ekwoge Blaise: So after that I can go ahead directly. I'll skip this way for the base questions that you gave us. I go down one of the questions here, and if I should take a run 3 way comparison, you're going to see the response for all the 3
Ekwoge Blaise: levels for the base, device, fine-tuning, and the GPU. All of it will be given here. If I should run that now, it's going to take some time, again, and my GPU and my collapse may leave me halfway, and I want to go on with this till the end. So.
Ekwoge Blaise: that is it for what was given to us for the work, but I had to go a little bit further. Of course, when I was showing my README file, I made use of certain things, like, for example, W and B, to be able to track live results on
Ekwoge Blaise: Let me just do that.
Ekwoge Blaise: So, yeah.
Ekwoge Blaise: How do I see? I want to be able to see.
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay, to be able to track my life results when I'm doing training, I actually have this installed, W&B, to be able to track that, and to be able to use, I made use of URO to quantify
Ekwoge Blaise: This… this one's…
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay. To be able to quantify my results, I use roads.
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay, so let me go ahead.
Ekwoge Blaise: So, for anybody who wants to start up with something, say, for example, I want to train for finance, finance and law, I'll just give you the domain that I want to train on, and I'll be able to go through the three, the three different stages, HMIs, instruction fine-tuning, and preference fine-tuning.
Ekwoge Blaise: So I'll choose my model. I've just seen one interesting implementation here that one other thing I could add here is to be able to allow the user to add any model of their choice. But for now what I have is I have some models that I've I've recoded.
Ekwoge Blaise: So, I can choose my model, for example, I choose this, and since I'm under pre-training, I'm going to go ahead to choose the data that I want. The data can be any data, it can be PDF, it can be a text file, it can be CVA, it can even be a scanned document, like, I have a scanned document here.
Ekwoge Blaise: And once the document loads, I can extract it. It can be from any domain that you you choose.
Ekwoge Blaise: And I go ahead to extract the data and preview it. You will see, just give it a little bit of time.
Ekwoge Blaise: Oh.
Ekwoge Blaise: So after training the model, while that is taking some time, I'll just be going ahead.
Ekwoge Blaise: After training the model, you can see it loading here. I don't know if it's visible for you.
Ekwoge Blaise: right? It's loading, and it's almost done. So after training that I'll use the model that I use for the pre-training for my supervisor.
Ekwoge Blaise: for my supervised instruction tuning the model that I'm going to have. I can easily reload it from here, and it's going to appear once I've done the training. Once I've done the training for for this.
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay? Since it's PDF and it's scanned PDF, it's taking some time. I made use of markup PDF, given that,
Ekwoge Blaise: biotesterrack was giving me some issues to extract using OCR and working on it with
Ekwoge Blaise: Google Collab. So I had to make use of Maka, since I'm using…
Ekwoge Blaise: I'm using Google and Google and Google App.
Ekwoge Blaise: So after training that, I'll feed the model to the supervised fine-tuning. I'll do the same thing for the supervised fine-tuning, and then I'll train that, and I'll feed the model for the ZPO. And then at the end of the day, I'll come to chat, if I'm on chat, and load the model
Ekwoge Blaise: I can see the model. The model is going to appear every model that I train. The model is going to appear, so I can actually directly ask questions to that particular model from this chat platform.
Ekwoge Blaise: when you go to the evaluate, you'll be able to evaluate whether you want to evaluate a single model, or you want to evaluate all the model. Of course, at the end of the day.
Ekwoge Blaise: Everything that you have used as training, you can just create a zip file of it, and then you download it, then upload it to…
Ekwoge Blaise: to, hogging face. Basically, that is it for my implementation. So, as per the quote, I do not
Ekwoge Blaise: I did a couple of things in addition, like I've just illustrated. But for the questions that we're giving, you see, for example.
Ekwoge Blaise: The base model will give you things in Chinese. I don't know if it's Chinese anyway. And after doing the supervised fine-tuning, I start getting better results, and of course, the ZPO gave me a much better result. So you'll get why I choose the ZPO.
Ekwoge Blaise: As well.
Ekwoge Blaise: As per the quantitative result, to be able to evaluate from the
Ekwoge Blaise: from the base model to the supervised fine tuning to the Dpo. You are going to be seeing this increase.
Ekwoge Blaise: This increase in… In the model, the performance of the different model.
Ekwoge Blaise: So, as a summary, like what I said earlier, initially, I trained Specifically for a held.
Ekwoge Blaise: in the health domain. We later on use that as a template to build, so that anybody, any user, anywhere, would be able to use that for any… to train any kind of… any kind of model.
Ekwoge Blaise: So, basically, I think that is it. Let me see if that has finished.
Ekwoge Blaise: Vehicles and training model.
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay, you see, the the document that I uploaded uploaded here is a scanned document. So scanned Pdf. You will automatically do everything in the back end and still extract the data.
Ekwoge Blaise: And this data, basically, this is the data.
Ekwoge Blaise: Yeah, it is showing that it is not the minimum, because I just have, I think, 4 pages. The document that I have just is about 4 pages, but the minimum that's only you gave was… you should get at least 50 paragraphs. So, I'll just change this… I'll change this to what you had.
Ekwoge Blaise: what I have here, which is text. This this wouldn't take long to upload while I'm
Ekwoge Blaise: So this gives me a data set of 110 paragraphs. So from there, I can go ahead to start the training. But before starting the training, I have all the parameters here. I can always change it, but the default from what I got from the classes is this.
Ekwoge Blaise: So the user can just use this default, or the user can use their own default values that they would want.
Ekwoge Blaise: And then after that, of course, you can start training.
Ekwoge Blaise: So the training this is going to take some time. So I'll I'm going to end my presentation here so that I don't go far off time. So thank you very much.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you, thank you very much.
Sunny: I think, your solution is also good, Egwok. I really liked it. It's a very minimalistic and very organized one, from the UI end, basically. Anyone can understand. So, good job.
Ekwoge Blaise: Okay, thank you so much.
Sunny: Thank you, sir. Thank you Okay, the next is Smith. Promita, would you like to share Grace.
Smit: Right, Sunny, I can go. No problem.
Sunny: It's metrics.
Smit: Yes.
Sunny: Yes, mate, please go ahead.
Smit: Yep, thanks.
Smit: So hello, everyone. My name is Smith. Today I'll be presenting my project.
Smit: As you can see, so if anyone wants to hit this URL, you will be able to see the same page that you guys are currently looking at.
Smit: Basically, this is the chat bot, which is the fine tune on my research paper that I can show.
Smit: Here, if you type the question regarding the bird, I don't know if you know, but the smallest bird in the world, if you type, and it will show which bird is the smallest bird.
Smit: I would like to type something else, so let's say… bird and hummingbird.
Smit: That will show exactly what it means.
Smit: And then I'll show…
Smit: different. I'll walk you through the the URL. Basically, what exactly I did for this project. What is the architecture of the project, and all.
Smit: Let's give it a minute because what it's doing in the backend, I can show you in the backend too
Smit: I can make this one small.
Smit: Give me one second… Yeah, so this is the,
Smit: This is the response from the chatbot.
Smit: So this chat bot is built using the Botpress right? So Botpress is the company which can give the Ui to build
Smit: a different chat bot. So for this project, let's, this is my, GitHub repo. This is the Hugging Face, repo.
Smit: I use the Llama 3.2 model.
Smit: And, of course, we use QLOAD as FD and DPO
Smit: and onslaught and Trl, right? what is the general purpose of the model? Right? Like, why, we need to do fine tuning, as we know that
Smit: all the LLMs that we currently have.
Smit: They… they will not give a domain-specific information, right? So… If you want to…
Smit: get our document specific answers, we usually fine tune the model, or we go with the right solution. Right? this is a just a comparison between the llama and also the
Smit: fine-tuned model.
Smit: And.
Smit: Basically, this is the architecture of what I did for the project.
Smit: I performed the fine tuning on lightning.ai. I had some issues with Google Colab. I ran out of the monthly consumption user. So I went with the lightning AI. I fine tune my model on lightning AI. Then I pushed my model to hugging face up.
Smit: Once I was in Hugging Face Hub, my model was fine-tuned.
Smit: I for homework 3. I already did the inferencing using the hugging face space. So I wanted to try some other solution.
Smit: that's when I came up with a model model is is the platform where we can push our model from the hugging face hub, and also it it will give the inferencing.
Smit: All right. So using the fast Api it gave me an endpoint for urgent rate which I can show you as well.
Smit: And after that the ui the chat bot it built using the bot press. Right? So basically, bot press is making the Api call to my model on to my model.
Smit: And once it receives the response, it is what is responding in the chat here.
Smit: right? And then at the end we will. You will see the response.
Smit: Yeah, in terms of 3 stages, as we all know, we have continued work, pre-training instruction, fine tuning and preference alignment.
Smit: These are a few of the parameters I just added in.
Smit: We are all aware of this one, so I will not be going in them in details.
Smit: Regarding my data set right? Where is the data coming from? If you go to this page? This is where the the research paper about the board is.
Smit: I use this paper as a starting point to fine tune my model.
Smit: And this page has this research paper has like 25 pages, but I use only 18 pages, because after that there only just a reference and annotation that were present.
Smit: Maybe if I can show pretty quickly.
Smit: So that we get some idea. So this was the research paper. And if you scroll down, if I go to
Smit: 25…
Smit: We will see that these are just the references that have been used by the author, so we don't need this information.
Smit: How? How is this? All the data sets are created. Right? I use cloths on it. 4.6 medium thinking model to paraphrase entire entire research paper. I can show you in in my Github as well. That data set.
Smit: And again, for generating the instruction pairs and reference pairs, I
Smit: I used the same model, Claude Sonnet, which generated me the synthesized data.
Smit: And then I try to fine tune the model. Now, the live demo we already did. What were some of the questions that were asked? Right? This were the question. These are like summarized form of the questions. So I ask 11 questions.
Smit: To the model, and this is just a comparison between base model SFT and the DPO.
Smit: And you can just click on one of them, and then we can see where
Smit: where the model succeed, and where where the specific phase failed. Right?
Smit: And at the end, some of the learning lessons, SFD, if you take a look, then SFD perform pretty well compared to DPO.
Smit: Dpo, during the DPO training, I used the epoch as a 5.
Smit: But
Smit: I found out that the Dpo is a little bit sensitive to the epox. If you use lesser epox, then then we might get accurate result. But for for the demo purpose I just put 5. For now I'd like to try some lower epoch version for the Dpo. I like 3 or one, and then see how it performs.
Smit: There's still a room for improvement for this project. I need to increase the data set. That's the that's the 1st thing that I would like to do. And also this is just a benchmark, right? Like, this is just a starting point for the project.
Smit: where, you know, we have the benchmark. Now, how can we improve or fine tune more on this specific topic?
Smit: If I can quickly show my, GitHub.
Smit: 2.
Smit: So this is the this is the Github with the same information.
Smit: I'll quickly show the data set to get some idea.
Smit: I'll just go to instruction data set.
Smit: So this is, again, generated by Claude Sonnet
Smit: All the data set that are being used on this project is by AI only, Claude.
Smit: preference.
Smit: So this is the data set. And then all the notebooks are attached here.
Smit: If you go to DPO alignment, DPO alignment is also Coming from,
Smit: a lightning AI. So we can see all the information here like what exactly the model did. What is the epoch? What was the training loss?
Smit: So this is the step that I would like to improve going forward right now. It's running at 5. I would like to decrease that in and try to see if I can fine tune more.
Smit: And then, again, the… all the reports are here.
Smit: Maybe I can quickly show final evaluation.
Smit: the the same criteria that were asked in the in the assignment, right? based model Sft and the Dpo, which one failed, which one passed. So the the on the website that I have it here. It's like a summarized version of what?
Smit: what is being done over here. So all the questions, 10 questions that are being asked.
Smit: But each question
Smit: what did model correct, predicted, and what was wrong, and what which model was good for that specific questions.
Smit: All the, ELAM questions are here.
Smit: And some of the final observations, as I mentioned earlier.
Smit: Sft improved consistently.
Smit: based on the data that was provided, which means that model is learning, which means that we are able to fine tune the model. Dpo did mismatch but Sfd. Was but occasionally regressed.
Smit: So which means that I need to improve our Dp a little bit. There's still room room for improvement. And again, this is the benchmark. So
Smit: whatever is presented here, it's just a, like, summarized version of the My GitHub repo.
Smit: So… I just wanted to show everyone if I can.
Smit: Minimize this.
Smit: Let's see.
Smit: For some reason, I'm not able to…
Smit: Let me just close this one.
Smit: Yeah, this this part. So whenever the the chat model is hit right, what is happening in the back end is this model is already on the model.com. All right. So it's it's on their server.
Smit: Whenever it will get hit, it will create a new container, right? So This is where…
Smit: the container will start model will be loaded from the model server, and then the inferencing will be made based on the information that will be provided by this model to the the front end, which is my ui.
Smit: And for that, I use the board press.
Smit: That's all.
Smit: PodPress idea, it came from Mayank's, no-code class, Sunny
Smit: They know, but they were recently discussing about that part. So I thought, including that in in my presentation.
Sunny: Okay.
Smit: No, no, that's fine.
Sunny: Great thing.
Sunny: Good, Smith, I think your solution was also good. I think many of you, like, you worked a very good, job, right? Every… everywhere I can see, like, a good UI and all, and…
Sunny: the managed code and the structure one. That's really great. Even though I haven't, taught so many things, means, I just taught on the… on that, like, the main concept level, but yeah, like…
Sunny: You even, did more than that, basically, on, over this software engineering and all, right? So… so many things you added, guys. That's really great.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so any more person would like to give their demonstration, please let me know, otherwise I will basically go for the voting, okay?
piyush sahyu: Okay.
Sunny: Okay, Mithul is there, and okay, Mithul, you…
piyush sahyu: I don'.
Sunny: So the tool shows down.
Mitul Shah: Should I go.
Sunny: And Piyush is there, right? 3 person is there.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so take 10-10 minutes, okay? So, Mithul, first you go, then Santosh, and then Piyush. Any more person is remaining?
Renjan Bhasi: Yeah, hey, this is Redgen here.
Sunny: And then you are also remaining.
Sunny: My name, this is.
Mayank Chugh: bank, yeah.
Sunny: Okay, Mayank is also there, right? Yeah, guys, so go one by one. First, Mithil, you.
Mitul Shah: Yep.
Mitul Shah: So, let me share my screen…
Mitul Shah: Can you see my screen?
Sunny: Yeah, I can see.
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so, I worked on e-commerce product assistant.
Mitul Shah: Basically, this is my dataset.
Mitul Shah: I will show all the datasets. I generated my datasets from ChatGPT,
Mitul Shah: This is my knowledge instruction data.
Mitul Shah: I took around 100 paragraphs for it.
Sunny: Mmhm.
Mitul Shah: This is my instruction data set.
Mitul Shah: Instruction input and output format.
Mitul Shah: There are around 100… Rose in this?
Mitul Shah: As you can see, wait, I think… yeah.
Mitul Shah: Let me minimize this.
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so there are around 100 examples in it, and in preference dataset as well, there are around 100 examples, chosen rejected form.
Mitul Shah: And I'm using the model, base model as Qwen 2.5, 0.5 billion.
Mitul Shah: And let me walk you through the code.
Mitul Shah: Wait, let me see whether I need to tell you anything in the README file.
Sunny: So, do one thing, Kaushik. If the code is same, right, the notebook and all, you can skip that part. You can directly showcase the evaluation matrixes, okay? Because the code would be the same, okay? There would not be any sort of changes. You can skip that part. If any new thing is there, new solution.
Mitul Shah: Yeah, I will just focus on the results, that's what I.
Sunny: Yeah, just focus over the result, right?
Mitul Shah: Okay, yeah. Yeah, so the… Code, basically, it's the same, like, base model, then instruction tuning, and then,
Mitul Shah: preference alignment, basically. These are the notebooks, and I have already run the notebooks, but let's not deep dive into that. I will show you the results, like…
Mitul Shah: Wait, let me move this to somewhere… Yeah, so… In…
Mitul Shah: Oh, wait! How do I show this?
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so in… there was one question in which there was a tie between… there was a tie between, like, the answers of both the questions. This is the question. How long does a refund take if I paid by credit card?
Mitul Shah: So, according to instruction fine-tuning model, the answer is, if you pay with credit card, the refund process typically takes 2 to 3 business days. The card issuer process
Mitul Shah: processes the transaction and sends a refund to your bank account within that time frame. The exact timeline can vary depending on the card network and the bank's processing speed. And according to the DPO model as well, this,
Mitul Shah: This question's answer is almost the same. See, I'm asking, this is the second question.
Mitul Shah: And this is the answer. If you pay with a credit card, the refund process typically takes 2 to 3 days, and, like, you can go along and it gives you the same answer. So, in the reports, if we go…
Mitul Shah: And in the final evaluation, if we go to that question, see there is a tie between those two questions. Sorry, for the answers between the questions, between DPO and SFT. So there was a tie. That's what I wanted to share. Then apart from that.
Mitul Shah: I created a chart, basically, to answer all the questions.
Mitul Shah: Oh.
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so there is a radar, I created a radar chart.
Mitul Shah: And, wait, this is unclear, so let's just focus on the bar chart.
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so I rated all the questions using Claude as a human being. So according to the base model, these are the values for correctness, helpfulness, domain accuracy, safety, and clarity.
Mitul Shah: According to SFT, these are the orange, orange ones are the values according to SFT and green ones are the values according to DPO.
Mitul Shah: Okay, so this is what I wanted to show, and apart from this.
Mitul Shah: I created a chatbot, which…
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so this is the chatbot which I wanted to show.
Mitul Shah: You can ask any question, like, how long does it… does the credit card refund take place?
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so it replied…
Mitul Shah: within a few seconds. A credit card refund can take anywhere from a few days to a few weeks, depending on the card issuer.
Mitul Shah: and the specific transaction. It's important to check with your card issuer to see how long it typically takes for a refund to be processed. So, let's just ask another question to it.
Mitul Shah: My card… Issuer is HDFC Bank.
Mitul Shah: Can you tell me?
Mitul Shah: How long?
Mitul Shah: Will it take… So, let's see what it responds.
Mitul Shah: I'm sorry, but I don't have access to your card issuer's information. Please provide me with the details of your card, and I will be happy to assist you. Yeah, so, like, this way you can keep chatting with it.
Mitul Shah: So this is what I wanted to show you. Apart from this, wait, let me see. I have made. I showed you the readme file. I showed you the data sets. I showed you the hugging phase. Then
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so this is how I created that file, to rate the responses by a human being, the bar chart which I showed you.
Mitul Shah: It is… it is done by Claude, but it was rated by a human being. I was trying to do it by another LLM, but I was facing a problem that, like, I… it should be paid, like, the… I need… I needed the payment account in… so I was not able to do it, I didn't have a payment account, so that's why I didn't do it.
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so, apart from it… Yeah, so I think I got everything apart from the code.
Mitul Shah: Code is just simple, like, this is non-instruction fine-tuning, installing the libraries, load the raw model, then clean the data.
Mitul Shah: Cleaning and chunking, then load the base model with onslaught.
Mitul Shah: Apply Laura.
Mitul Shah: Train on the raw text.
Mitul Shah: This is reducing the loss.
Mitul Shah: save the Stage 1 adapter, and then…
Mitul Shah: I'm pushing it to the hugging face.
Mitul Shah: And then, just as the model…
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so that… this is pretty much it, and yeah, same thing, like, these two, instruction, fine-tuning, and EPO.
Mitul Shah: alignment files.
Mitul Shah: Yeah, so I think this is it from my side. If you want me to share something else, just let me know.
Sunny: Okay, okay, Mittal, I think this is great.
Sunny: You can share the GitHub link in the chat, okay, so everyone can go through with your solution. If anyone would be having any question, they can ask in the chat itself, right?
Sunny: Yeah, thank you. Thank you, Muttal. Great work. Thank you very much.
Mitul Shah: Thank you.
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: Now, Santosh, Pius, anyone is there? Please go ahead.
Santosh: Yeah, yeah, it's sunny. Yeah, I can. I can.
Sunny: Yes, Santos, you can go.
Santosh: Hey, hey guys, I don't want to take much of everyone's time, since we're already late, I know. And also, mine is pretty similar to most of the stuff everybody showcased already.
Santosh: I wanted to just, share the, the live demo, what I've done, but yeah, I wanted to present both,
Santosh: things I have developed. One is, like, finance, AIHR bot. Another one is multi-domain, which, unfortunately, just now my collab got disconnected. If I run, it will take another 20 minutes to reach to the final, but anyway, that's pretty similar to the other demo, which I'm going to present, where additional thing in the multi is where you can select, domain.
Santosh: Like, either, list of domains I have, like, help desk, e-commerce, and everything, whatever presented in the…
Santosh: Assignment, right? Where you can select the domain, ask a specific question, you get an answer. But this is a subset of that multi-domain notebook. I made it into just specific to finance. So the behavior is same. Only thing is just a selection of the domain and asking the question is different.
Santosh: So just… I'll run it, and I'll get back to the deliverables, what I've done so far in this assignment. So here, very similar. You ask the question, you can select the temperature and the max number of tokens, which you can expect in the response. So it is simple.
Santosh: Just a widget app, in Python you have. I used it. I did not leverage any of other apps. The other people who demonstrated, I used just Colab here.
Santosh: So, I went to, yeah, this is the app, right now it's running, you see, when I put, is it safe to use the net banking on public Wi-Fi?
Santosh: Yes, the answer we have got. I can run a couple more questions to showcase.
Santosh: So.
Santosh: So it's running, and here, the…
Santosh: So this is the final — this widget is running on the DPO, the final adapter, which I got out of the preference training. So that's answers coming from preference. Similarly, I had this widget for every stage.
Santosh: Here, I merged all the stage 1, stage 2, stage 3 into one, notebook, combined everything here, run through the same set, non-instruction, dataset at the initial, and then generated the
Santosh: non-instruction model, and then, applied the LoRa, QLoRa, and then…
Santosh: run through another here app. I will do the train initial stage one training I use this. The model is quen 2.5 5 billion parameter model as a base. And
Santosh: The number of, examples I used in the instruction is, 50, and then the number of epochs, just 1, and then total steps, it's 5. And here it shows the loss, how it continued, and reduced it to 1.8, and also here I put the evaluation.
Santosh: How? How does a base model evaluation run on the data set I provided?
Santosh: Here is the output, the question it took, and the base model answer, and the problem, what it is for.
Santosh: Similarly, I had an interactive demo on the stage one, which is very, very similar, but it produces a different output when you compare with SFT and DPO, and went through similar steps, which everybody familiar with on the SFT.
Santosh: Same thing, here, I had a comparison. I'll show you the comparison based on the 10 questions.
Santosh: So and also I did a evaluation on 3 stages. I'll show you that in a minute. Here, if I go
Santosh: Yeah, here, the comparison across all the one, and here it shows some of the
Santosh: results, it showed, Thai, and some of them SFTP is better, some of them on DPO. It depends, right? The amount of data I used is very small. If I get into large and then fine-tune it more, I definitely… I believe that DPO would,
Santosh: Break, others, outright, so that's the basic, you know, I.
Santosh: develop this to understand my knowledge and based on the training. So I now I got pretty much how the fine tune works, and what are the stages included, and all that.
Santosh: Coming to the code, I put in, in GitHub. I put the both, the multi-domain one, where, if you go here, non-instruction, where the data is by domain, I put, you know, each,
Santosh: each domain, in our instruction here. If you go to the stage 2, you have, by… I put the by domain.
Santosh: instruction data set, similarly DPO. So that's the first submission I made, but later I realized I thought I did more, and then I went with only just finance, and I wanted to showcase more deep into that. Because of time constraint, I just running fast to give a chance to other folks.
Santosh: But all the deliverables are here, the reports, evaluation, final evaluation, and everything.
Santosh: the I I created the inference script also. So if before running this that widget, I just went through inference script based on the assignment requirement. And then later, I do something I want to show just graphically. So I I went with this. So that's pretty much guys.
Santosh: Any questions, I'll put my GitHub link in the chat. Please let me know if you have any questions.
Sunny: Yeah, Santosh, so you can paste your solution also in the chat.
Sunny: If anyone would be having question, they will ask you, okay?
Sunny: Yeah, again, again, it's, like, good, and the nice, means it's a clean practical, basically, and I think you applied all, all the learning which you, which you have learned in the live classes, correct? So, yeah, that's, that's great, Santos. Thank you, thank you for the demonstration.
Sunny: Now the next person is…
piyush sahyu: Hello, sir.
Sunny: Piyush is there, right?
piyush sahyu: Yep.
piyush sahyu: And.
piyush sahyu: Yeah, Piyush, Mayank,
Sunny: Yeah, you can go ahead.
Sunny: Okay.
piyush sahyu: Okay, so…
Sunny: And then.
Sunny: Last candidate is Ranjan, right?
Sunny: Ranjan.
piyush sahyu: It's just.
Sunny: So, yeah, there's 3% on the pending one. Please go ahead with your, solution, Piyush.
piyush sahyu: the… I mean, I mean.
Sunny: If any repetitive thing is there, then please cut out that and just showcase the necessary part, okay?
piyush sahyu: Okay, sir. So, my screen is visible right now.
Sunny: Yeah, it is visible.
piyush sahyu: Okay, so just start with the… I like my…
piyush sahyu: project like, basically, the problem statement was, if like in any company, if you go like any employee, so they have many queries. But but Hr. Like can't respond to everyone. So I made a chat board, basically and using up company policy data and fine tune it.
piyush sahyu: And then…
piyush sahyu: And on this basis, like, the… any… anyone employed can ask question to the chatbot. So basically, like,
piyush sahyu: You can say that what problem it's solved. I will share the link. Everyone can check it. So this is the structure, basically. How it is started, basically. At first, I use a handbook at 40 pages.
piyush sahyu: and then extract the whole, process using the codes that provided, and then I will, start, fine-tuning at, non-instruction base. So, I, I do multiple, like, training, because I don't find, like,
piyush sahyu: actual response that I was, want to, like, so after, like, tuning so many, many times for parameters and all, so that I found the perfect parameter, then I start training on the parameters.
piyush sahyu: Then I go for the supervised fine-tuning. Here, the difficulty was the, like after training, like at first stage, my model start, like, go in a state of catastrophic, where the model start answering from his pre-trained data, not on a, like, handbook. So I give the, in supervised fine-tuning, I give the model,
piyush sahyu: like a supervisor data. Actually, the search said in the classes like instruction, input and output. And I like, I use like cloudy for that. So basically here, like, I generate my all of data using cloudy at 1st the handbook, and then the Sft. And all all my data for the like, and it cover all the categories for me.
piyush sahyu: So I can get the better data set for my human synthetic data for my training. So after like supervised fine tuning, I go for the DPU basically cause my model still answer in a very robotic format. So I go for the DPU and I perform like direct preference optimization in my
piyush sahyu: like a stage two and at stage three I am merged with the stage two model and I provide a very unique data in very simple response manner as you can see.
piyush sahyu: like here in the data set like the answer is very short and new like accurate. The chosen one and the rejected one is not like what? What are the problems I face in my stage? 2. I give it to the cloudy and tell that generate me such kind of synthetic human preference data that it will helpful for training at a Dpo.
piyush sahyu: So, basically, this is the whole… my…
piyush sahyu: Like, training thing, and
piyush sahyu: Like, I can show you, like, here's the, all the code part, which is not required, basically, because everyone have the same code, and I just, for, tune some parameters for my, like, specific purpose, and I changed twice or thrice of time models, like, from Tiny Llama to Q, like, when 2.5, 3 billion parameter to 1.5 billion parameter.
piyush sahyu: So I, like, I found my best,
piyush sahyu: fitted model for my training, and here you can see, like, everything. So, basically, Also.
piyush sahyu: I like whatever is written in here, like I get from the like training. I write it here like basically at stage one, what are the like objective data method and all.
piyush sahyu: So basically I use 200 draw paragraph then like it's alpaca style question answer basically and 220 chosen rejected players basically and then.
piyush sahyu: Like, this is the answer from, like, these notebooks, like, at base queen, what are the responses, and SFT level, what are the responses, and at DPO level, what are the responses.
piyush sahyu: So, like, how many days, sick days. So, here, you can see that these are the responses of each, each and every stages. And at the DPO level, what are the improvements? So, at DPO level.
piyush sahyu: like the problem we face at a stage like one hallucination, and also like answering from his pretend data. Then at a like at a stage 2, we found that elimination eliminated reputation like, if you train the like model at like a few lesser learning rate. So it will start like
piyush sahyu: answer answer in a very repetitive manner so these were these were fixed in at a DPO level and
piyush sahyu: And, yeah, this is all the…
piyush sahyu: Thing that I found, like, found during, like, I learned during all this fine tuning process and there is also a report
piyush sahyu: Actually, I made… But, miss.
piyush sahyu: Like whatever I like a problem definition.
piyush sahyu: technical challenges, I… whatever I, like, feel that I, face in… during, the training part, I write it to the, like, co-pilot, and it generates me this kind of, README file. So, I… everything, in human text, I give it to the…
piyush sahyu: Copilot, and it will write everything in a structured manner.
piyush sahyu: So these are the train methodology what I used in my training specifically.
piyush sahyu: And these are the losses that reduces by after training.
piyush sahyu: And, yeah, so basically now come to the inferencing part. So.
piyush sahyu: Actually, I'm, like, I made this front end, and I also deploy it.
piyush sahyu: But the only thing is that at my backend was not deployed at Hugging Face space due to, like, space, like, when Hugging Face provide only 1GB RAM, and my model was beyond that, so I was unable to, deploy it, but when I, able to deploy it.
piyush sahyu: So this is, this was the interface and here, like, I can like ask question and from the backend it'll answer through it.
piyush sahyu: And,
piyush sahyu: for now, I can… I… I can do the influencing part from, like, CoLab, so I already prepared this setup for the influencing part, and
piyush sahyu: This one, yeah, this one. So actually, if I again, right, so,
piyush sahyu: again, this is the issue which I always face during the training, and, like, import issue, so I can't, but,
piyush sahyu: I store already store my sum of hands influencing part answer.
piyush sahyu: I.
piyush sahyu: Good.
piyush sahyu: This one.
piyush sahyu: Yeah, so, here…
piyush sahyu: Here I inference adapted training time. So can I request feedback from people outside my immediate team if any employee ask this question? So my model responses is this like, I'm not sure about that. Can you provide more details? So it's not like model will answer each and every time, even if it not train on such data. Like I also give a system prompt, like system prompt.
piyush sahyu: to the my model so that it will like deny if if he don't know the answer of the particular question.
piyush sahyu: So, basically… And at last, yeah.
piyush sahyu: So this, this, these are the,
piyush sahyu: These are the you are a Nexora technology policy assistant answer using only the handbook. If info is missing, say no, do don't use header or list. Basically, it will not answer if he don't know the data in his pretend by using his pretend data. So what are the goals of Nexora technology for future? So here is the responses from the my model.
piyush sahyu: At DPO after training at a DPO level.
piyush sahyu: So, you can say that he answered it, and
piyush sahyu: how many years do I get in a year? So, like, leave. I'm sorry, but I don't have information. If something's not written in notebook, it will totally deny the fact that we don't know the answer, and you have to, like, ask to the department to… about your query.
piyush sahyu: And what are the future implementation we can do? So basically, in future, I can apply RAG. And like, I feel that in this whole process, I feel that we don't need to train model from like at a non-instruction. As Anisa said that in classes that we don't need to like train model from non-struction.
piyush sahyu: And we can also train model from supervised fine-tuning. And we can perform like we can use RAG and provide those handbook data to the RAG and stored in VectorDB. And it will generate more and better answer at influencing rather than training the whole model because
piyush sahyu: if in future, if the company policy change, so we can't train model again and again. So we we can go for the rag based model.
piyush sahyu: Yeah, sir, so this is my part.
piyush sahyu: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah, okay, great, Piyush, thank you for the demonstration.
Sunny: It was really good, and thank you for putting all the efforts.
Sunny: Great. So now, yeah, yeah.
abhishek kadiyala: I don't understand.
Mayank Chugh: Thank you.
Sunny: See, 4 person are there, Mayank. Ranjan, are you there? Ranjan?
Renjan Bhasi: Yeah, I'm.
Sunny: Okay, Naveen is also here, Abhishek is also here. Okay, first, Mayank, you can go.
Sunny: Yeah, I don't know.
Mayank Chugh: It doesn't take much time. Yep, yep, yep. Give me.
Sunny: Yeah, guys, so take, take 5 minutes, 5 to 10 minutes, okay, between that, and, showcase the, the, basically, important thing, okay, not the repetitive one. If you have implemented.
Mayank Chugh: I couldn.
Sunny: Any new thing, then showcase that, okay?
Mayank Chugh: Yep.
Sunny: Yep.
Mayank Chugh: Thanks, Annie. Thanks for your guidance and teaching. It's in depth. And thanks for sharing, actually. Thanks for
Mayank Chugh: Appreciating my work. And I have shared my things in the LinkedIn as well. I have created a YouTube video as well for this. So I'll not go through in that depth, because everything is available in the my YouTube channel as well, if somebody wants to go through. Thanks, everyone. And thanks, Sunny as well. So teaching us in that much depth.
Mayank Chugh: And, so detailed. I have seen a lot of outstanding solutions. I don't have that much, done that much in depth, because I was going to keep it in the, space of that, scope of that, this,
Mayank Chugh: challenge. So, mine is basically a finance FAQ assistant. I have done the fine-tune… fine-tune with the onslaught in the notebooks, in the Google Colab. I stay… all three stages, non-instruct… non-instruction fine-tuning, instruction fine-tuning, and then DPO. All in GP… Google Colab… Colab things are there.
Mayank Chugh: So, I'll show the results as, so initially it was, Sunny told that, first result, then walk through the problem and then data. And if required, we can go live with this.
Mayank Chugh: So this is my results. I have stage one, which is basically with non-instruction data where we have only only data. It is around 2.069659. And then second one is basically stage two instruction data.
Mayank Chugh: Where we have our instructions and the response, it is 2.0564, and then it reduced a lot in 0.299.
Mayank Chugh: One thing I, basically, I would just want to show that why it was, basically, when I go with the
Mayank Chugh: Any question? What is SIP? Base model will always say, sorry, I'm sorry, I don't know the answers and all.
Mayank Chugh: But when it comes to, good models or after training, it's supposed to give that answer. But one honest, what I have noticed, for the after DPO as well, sometimes it is giving me a, a fake, or, or basically, non…
Mayank Chugh: corrective response, which is basically I say that what is SIP is to say something different, what is not, it is supposed to be a systematic one.
Mayank Chugh: systematic investment, plan, but it is not that… giving that much. So, that was… I have noticed, and also, when I was doing it, Google Collab was also… because of first stage, output is required for second stage, second stage output is required for third stage. So, it was giving me, it was…
Mayank Chugh: Breaking it all a lot. So that's what the problem I faced.
Mayank Chugh: So similarly, as everyone, I have used for the second stage, I have used the 2.5 billion structured data.
Mayank Chugh: And, anything… I think there's nothing much. I've used the GPU, free GPU, and, all these things are same. And, we have used the same raw data instructions, and then same. Nothing much in this. I have… first, I have used… for stage one, I have used 57 rows.
Mayank Chugh: raw data, and, second one is stage one, we have, I, I had around 104, rows of question, instruction and response. The third one is around 51. Stage three, where we have,
Mayank Chugh: Questions, choose, and then, the other one, rejected one, as all we have used, I have used.
Mayank Chugh: And, Yes, and that's it. I think it is about that, and…
Mayank Chugh: Ppt done, let me show, I think it's all same, nothing much difference over here.
Mayank Chugh: It's my Github. I'll share that Github as well. So the results are same. I have kept the everything in my repository, all the results, evolutions, and everything is in the same way. I think many of the many of Sumit, Dipti, and others. Everyone have done the same way. I think it's
Mayank Chugh: Thanks to AI, it's giving us everyone the same kind of solutions.
Mayank Chugh: And I've used Claude for these things. I have also pushed my models to GitHub. And also, basically, for first stage, I'm using the second stage. I'm using it from the GitHub.
Mayank Chugh: I have also that uploaded in my local in my Google Colab as well. If it is not taking it from Google Colab from the hugging face, it will take from my local like that I have.
Mayank Chugh: done the coding as well in that. This is separately, which is not given by the cloud. I have added from my side.
Mayank Chugh: This is all about all three notebooks are here. I have added up basically it's a self-learning kind of a notes I tried. I have used the same thing, same way. I think everyone have done that. That's great. But thing else is much every stage, what all things we are using in every stage, I have done the same way.
Mayank Chugh: But I have tried my level best to keep it in the scope of the, this,
Mayank Chugh: Yeah, challenge. And… yeah, this is my…
Mayank Chugh: Somebody was saying that how to open that one. If you open the markdown file, you will get the result with this way. But if you'll
Mayank Chugh: properly, if you'll see that markdown results, it will come up with this way. You can use this URL, it's markdown-pages.dev, you can get these things, properly view that,
Mayank Chugh: Yep.
Mayank Chugh: Alright.
Mayank Chugh: Second. Yeah. So it will be similar.
Mayank Chugh: Oops.
Mayank Chugh: I think I can see it without this as well.
Mayank Chugh: Need to move…
Mayank Chugh: Yes, I think, yeah. So this is basically architecture diagram, which is also there in, in, in my GitHub, GitHub. Let me open my GitHub. So all GitHubs, it's, if you'll go in the presentations, architecture diagrams.
Mayank Chugh: It is also there.
piyush sahyu: Actually, your screen is not visible.
Sunny: Yeah, I think you are sharing a single screen. Share the entire…
Mayank Chugh: Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry about it.
Mayank Chugh: Let me correct it, to correct this one.
Mayank Chugh: Why?
Mayank Chugh: I tried to screen to, you know…
Mayank Chugh: Now, is it visible?
piyush sahyu: No, actually, go to the share tab and, like, choose a complete entire screen selection.
Mayank Chugh: Oh, okay. I have done that. I just see if, here… We've done it again.
Mayank Chugh: Not, and…
Mayank Chugh: Is it still not visible?
Sunny: The architecture part is visible, you can explore.
Mayank Chugh: Yeah, this one I'm showing. Actually, this is the architecture part. All these, I think I have missed all things. Basically, this is the architecture part, and the mermaid things I was showing here.
Mayank Chugh: Where it is? Yeah, this one. Basically, if you want to see that, how the result is, if you'll have to see the mermaid or any MD file proper way, you have to… means you have to see it properly in the mermaid architecture things, this will come, because mermaid is…
Mayank Chugh: In the code, it will look like this, but here, it will look like this. I think, those who don't know, only for those.
Mayank Chugh: So, this is architecture and FAQ.
Mayank Chugh: I have kept all the data here, similar as everyone.
Mayank Chugh: And… In fact, I have kept the, my, each stage's output as well. Reports are here.
Mayank Chugh: Similar, 10 questions are there in this one.
Mayank Chugh: Oh, anything else?
Mayank Chugh: Nothing much. Yeah, I think I am done. Nothing much. I have… I have also,
Mayank Chugh: created a YouTube video. If somebody wants to go through that, all the libraries, all the, all the notebooks, it's, it's available. I think it's not that much, in that. One thing I was showing that I'm using it and uploading it in the notebook, this is, these are my three notebooks. I just want to show
Mayank Chugh: It was you.
Sunny: Yeah, you can share the link in the chat also, or Mayank, okay? About your solution and all, whatever you've created over the YouTube, okay?
Mayank Chugh: Yep, yep, yep, please. Yep, I'll do that. It's basically, yeah, it's in GitHub. Everything, if somebody will want to touch it and touch with me, they can go with the GitHub account. Everything is available from GitHub too. They can go. Thank you, thank you. I'll share that. Thank you, thank you, thank you. I'll not take much time.
Sunny: No, thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, Ranjan, you can go ahead now.
Renjan Bhasi: Yeah, thank you, Sunny. So I know everybody's tired, so I'll not take much time either. Hello, all. My name is Srinjan.
Renjan Bhasi: I cannot do the demonstration now, because I was running my collab from the morning, thinking that I'll be presenting, but just realized that I am out of the supported memory, so I'm trying to run it in a CPU, but I just realized that
Renjan Bhasi: Save on this one. It is not responding. Like, you know, I think it's never going to finish, so I cannot do a live demo.
Renjan Bhasi: The only thing I can show is I just captured a screenshot of the application. But even before I go there, I'll just explain what I should do.
Renjan Bhasi: I just tried the… a customer support assistant chatbot is what I tried to build. And
Renjan Bhasi: I run the solution in Colab. The source code is all uploaded to the JIT. So if you see here, I have three notebooks. I don't want to walk you through because, you know, it is mostly similar to
Renjan Bhasi: The same solution you all did. At a high level, I have a non-instruction fine-tuning. I used the Llama 3.3 billion model.
piyush sahyu: Keen is not visible.
Renjan Bhasi: Oh, sorry. I have to share my screen.
Renjan Bhasi: It's my best.
Renjan Bhasi: Can you see my screen now?
Mayank Chugh: Yes.
abhishek kadiyala: No.
Renjan Bhasi: All right, thank you
Renjan Bhasi: Yeah, I will try to wind it up much faster. I was trying to say I also selected a similar approach, started with the non-instruction fine tuning using the Llama model.
abhishek kadiyala: Okay.
abhishek kadiyala: Well,
Renjan Bhasi: The 3.23 billion model is what I tried. I saved it to my local box. And then I tried to come up with a instruction fine-tuned model.
abhishek kadiyala: Hello.
Renjan Bhasi: That is also saved. And then finally, I had a BPO alignment using the alignment data. So I can show you the three —
Renjan Bhasi: Oh.
Renjan Bhasi: Data files, I created a…
Renjan Bhasi: my own instruction data in a CSV file, and then I have instruction data in a JSON file, and a preference data in the JSON format as well. And the final DPA model is what I saved, and I uploaded this to Hugging Face. You can see it here.
Renjan Bhasi: And this is the model of finally I.
abhishek kadiyala: the…
Renjan Bhasi: upload to Gradio using Collab. But unfortunately, I'm not able to demonstrate that now because I just ran out of GPU storage. I'm running this model in CPU, so just a simple hello also is not responding. So that is what I cannot demo.
Renjan Bhasi: I just captured a screenshot of,
Renjan Bhasi: my application, just to make sure, like, I can have a copy of that. So this is how my chatbot was looking like.
Renjan Bhasi: I just asked some basic questions here, and, you know, I got some response. I'm trying to zoom it a little bit.
Renjan Bhasi: Not sure you can see it, but I captured the reports, the final report. Maybe that's what I can show at this point. Give me one second.
Renjan Bhasi: Not sure this is visible.
Renjan Bhasi: So I just compared around the 10 sample questions and compared against the base model, SFT model, and my final DPO preference model one. And this is the results I see. One thing I noticed, the way I trained or maybe the data we have.
Renjan Bhasi: I see almost similar results between the SFT model response and the DPO one. Only a couple of them I see the DPO was having a slightly better result, but most of the other scenarios it was almost similar.
Renjan Bhasi: I noticed that some of the previous demos also, I see that a similar kind of a thing, not sure, is it because of the
Renjan Bhasi: less number of, data that we used, but that is one of the observations I had, you know, in this whole process. The challenges, I tried to use the TinyLlama initially for my model training, and, I didn't get a better result, from my
Renjan Bhasi: Sft model or the DPU model, so that's why I went to the… the bigger, LLAMA model. Not sure, like, any of you have similar experience, but…
Renjan Bhasi: I struggled a lot. Initially, I was not sure why my training is not effective. My losses were in the range of more than two. Once I changed the model from Tiny Lemma to the bigger one.
Renjan Bhasi: I suddenly see, like, without any changes, the training was effective, and the,
Renjan Bhasi: the losses were, you know, coming down. So that is one observation I had, not sure about others. So this is just how I deployed, but as I said, I cannot show you the radio one.
Renjan Bhasi: Obviously the approach. I'll just quickly explain, even though it is a little repetitive. We have 3
Renjan Bhasi: stages the non instruction fine tuning in stage one.
Renjan Bhasi: And then instruction fine-tuning on stage 2 was using the SFT model to apply the LoRa and QLoRa
Renjan Bhasi: To make sure that, like, we are not using a lot of GPU space. And finally, use the DPO alignment, in the Stage 3. So these are all my LoRa, QLoRa configuration, 16 rank, and, this other information you can see here.
Renjan Bhasi: Nothing different or unique. I have some of the screenshots taken from my final demonstration.
Renjan Bhasi: the future improvements. What I'm thinking that I can do is you know, this 1st one I already tried like using the Lama 3 1 billion model.
Renjan Bhasi: I can apply an automatic evaluation, I can try an RPO, I can apply a RAG over the Help Center, so I can, you know.
Renjan Bhasi: be relevant, like, you know, once policy or information are getting changed, and, I can also extract this, as a GGUF model, to run on my CPU. I didn't try that, that's why I'm struggling to run on my CPU alone, Colab.
Renjan Bhasi: So these are the few things I'm thinking, like, I can improve in the future. This is my structure, and, my entire source code is uploaded to, my JIT. This is, the solution, so I have all the solution already uploaded.
Renjan Bhasi: I'll stop my presentation. If anybody have any queries, let me know. But otherwise, thank you all.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you, Rajan, thank you for the demonstration.
Sunny: Oh.
Sunny: Okay, so who's the next, one?
Sunny: Naveen, are you there? Yeah, I'm here.
Naveen: Yeah, I'm Navin. I'm here. Yeah.
Sunny: So, you can go, guys. I think you are the last folks. So, Naveen first, you, and Abhishek.
Naveen: Sure, sure.
Sunny: Yep.
Naveen: Okay, so… I'm sharing my screen. I want to be respectable of others' time here.
Naveen: So, let me straight away take you through the… Report that is coming out.
Naveen: So, after we run all the three stages of the pipeline, so…
Naveen: The results are uploaded into,
Naveen: Hugging Face, and here is my…
Naveen: One hour back when I ran, this is a… Report that came out.
Naveen: So one of the questions that I see, so the problem statement is I'm actually fine-tuning the LLM for insurance data. So I work on insurance domain, so my objective is to take a small model and then train some insurance on that so that it can give insurance-specific terminologies, it can answer the user based on.
Naveen: The insurance verbiage.
Naveen: So, with that intention, I've taken a small model, trained it on some insurance terminology. I basically used some Kaplan source material, the PDF, and then passed it as a raw file, and using that, started fine-tuning the model there.
Naveen: Okay, so end of the day, this is the report, evaluation report that comes out. My experience working with the leadership is they typically ask on a scale of 10 or a scale of 100, how do you rate your model, right? So that's the reason we come up… we came up with a normalized score.
Naveen: So I'm using an Llama 3.1 that is a judge model. So this model actually evaluates the output that is coming out from all the three stages and then creating this report.
Naveen: So this is something that I did differently, that's the reason I'm bringing it up here, but the rest of the Stage 1, Stage 2, Stage 3 training pretty much remains the same as what others have done.
Naveen: So for each question that we have asked, on a scale of 10, it's, rating. So this is before even the fine-tuning, any kind of Stage 1, training. Base model gave me this kind of, score.
Naveen: After non-instruction fine-tuning, this is the score, instruction fine-tuning, and then finally the preference score. For each question, the prompt that we have sent, the base model response, non-instruction response, instruction response.
Naveen: Preference model response and the overall score, so we are quantifying it. The judge model is basically quantifying and giving a winner out of these different alignments that we have done, and then the justification behind that. So this is the final report that comes out, which has a very detailed analysis of.
Naveen: the summary here.
Naveen: So any questions on this?
Naveen: So here I have loaded my dataset, in Hugging Face. Let me quickly run through the…
Naveen: Architecture diagram, that way… Give me a minute, please.
Naveen: So, this is an insurance AI agent. So, as discussed, I'm taking a small model, a model, and then just,
Naveen: training the insurance terminology on top of that. And this is my architecture. I'm having Hugging Face repo, where I have my raw files. I'm pulling the raw files, passing it with the base model, which is 2.5.
Naveen: So, before even sending the raw data, I'm evaluating the base model, and then, creating a report out of it, and then fine-tuning this,
Naveen: base model with the raw data, and then saving the model and saving the report back into Hugging Face.
Naveen: And then, on the trained model, I'm evaluating it, getting a report, and storing it back to Hugging Face. This is my stage 1.
Naveen: Stage 2, I'm using that output from the Stage 1, loading it, and then training it on the instruction…
Naveen: non-instruction data set.
Naveen: Sorry, instruction data set here.
Naveen: Stage 3, the same thing,
Naveen: training it on the preference data set.
Naveen: And then, finally, generating a report. And this is something that I've done differently, where I'm loading a LAMA model, a judge model, and it will evaluate the results coming out from all the three models, and then creating a quantitative score, and then declaring which model is doing better.
Naveen: And then that's saving back into the Hugging Face repo.
Naveen: That's about my, project, and then, and further, I would like to enhance this with some company-specific data, do some ragging, and then on top of that, do, build some agentic, solutions so that, we can, automate certain tasks.
Naveen: That's about my… do let me know if you have any questions on that.
Sunny: Yeah, definitely you can enhance this solution going forward.
Sunny: And I think you selected a good domain, okay?
Sunny: Great.
Naveen: And thanks for the Krishna Academy and Sunny. I mean, this kind of demo really helps me to expose to different solutions, and
Naveen: meet different people who are, like, like-minded and who are thinking in different directions. Thanks, Sunny.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you, thank you, Navid. Okay, so today's last demonstration. Abhishek, can you please go ahead?
abhishek kadiyala: Yes, sir.
Sunny: I'm on.
abhishek kadiyala: Are you hear me, s
abhishek kadiyala: Hello?
Sunny: You can start. Yeah, we can hear you. Please go ahead.
abhishek kadiyala: Thank you for giving opportunity.
abhishek kadiyala: Yeah, I'm, work on the project, like, like, targeting the whoever the clinics are not, supporting to, fine-tune their model or model, like, they are waiting in, for, doctors' answers who are not answering to the clients, like, patients.
abhishek kadiyala: So, I targeting the, domains like,
abhishek kadiyala: clinics of, like, hair, skin, and dental. The… I specifically, through these three domains, and I believe that I gather the data,
abhishek kadiyala: specific data for the three clinics, and I, I, I import the data to the learning succession, as you, who are folks to, do our previous, in, payment, link.
abhishek kadiyala: Presentation, and…
abhishek kadiyala: those are same process. I will be implemented like long section, using a Laura and and then a second stage, maybe instructions, and maybe third in the reference tuning.
abhishek kadiyala: Like, I cannot share a live demo.
abhishek kadiyala: Using a DBO.
abhishek kadiyala: Yeah.
abhishek kadiyala: You can ask any questions to check my model, like, about skin, dental, and… -Hu
abhishek kadiyala: Yeah, for example, my details.
abhishek kadiyala: For example, my team.
abhishek kadiyala: It's a lot.
abhishek kadiyala: Ask me a question like this.
abhishek kadiyala: Yeah, it's giving an answer, like, LOTPs are among the most common complaints, like, receiving the dental professionals, like, something, something, blah, blah, blah. So, like, this is, helping the questions to the… if the user asks any questions, then, my board automatically, reply to the…
abhishek kadiyala: Client, for… without a…
abhishek kadiyala: waiting for the, who are receptionists or doctors answering, so it may be helpful for many more people, so I will be trying to implement in… who are not, like, fine-tuning their own model. I will be very,
abhishek kadiyala: helpful to the… for those who give, help to the, like, who… that clinic. I will, so that's my main goal, and this is my project.
abhishek kadiyala: Hello. Sounds good.
abhishek kadiyala: Yep.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, yeah, I am hearing.
abhishek kadiyala: Yeah, so this is not if you go final output, I am…
abhishek kadiyala: the, the stored state I am, sent to the output I am import, importing from, the drive, and, and then I will, like, folders, like, creating the folders pass, this,
abhishek kadiyala: And posted it by importing, like, installing the onslaught.
abhishek kadiyala: Second step, like, just fine-tuning the model using a deep divorce.
Sunny: Yeah, your voice is low, but yeah, I can see your solution. I think it is more around the notebook and all, but yeah.
abhishek kadiyala: Okay.
Sunny: That is also a good thing, at least you tried and you have created a final model, correct?
abhishek kadiyala: Yes, sir, yes.
Sunny: Yeah, good.
Sunny: Okay, Abhishek, I think,
abhishek kadiyala: Yeah, yeah, you can also test that something, any, what are the problems you're facing, maybe skin, around the skin, teeth, and, in chat also, you can, ask any questions, I will be paste here, and you can check my model through it.
Sunny: Mmhm
Sunny: Yeah, definitely, you can do otherwise, and even you can keep it over the Hugging Face space also, and you can give that link to everyone in the community chat, so that people can try out your model, okay?
abhishek kadiyala: Okay. Yeah.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so I'm sharing a link with all of you, and please let us… let me know that whose solution was a good one.
Sunny: So that we can decide the final, winner, okay?
Sunny: And we can select at least top 3 person, and I can,
Sunny: According to my promise, guys, I can provide the access of that advanced batch, okay?
Sunny: So you can give your, board over here. I, I pasted the link in the chat, please open that.
Mayank Chugh: Sunny, one more thing. Is it possible to ask everyone or you can can can somebody create or putting that whatever they have a they have a solutions putting that GitHub solution or anywhere in some form or.
Sunny: I have all the names, I will keep… I will take your GitHub link, and I'll put it in the resource section, okay? Don't worry.
Mayank Chugh: Okay, sure.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so you can provide your, boards.
Sunny: I shared the link,
Sunny: Please give as much as board, so that we can finalize the… Winner, okay?
Sunny: So, this many person has given the demonstration today. It is around 17 names, actually. 17 demonstrations we have completed, within 4 hours of time.
Sunny: Yeah, only one vote you can cast. This is a link, Deepthi, you can check out this link. I pasted it in the chat, okay? Open the chat.
Sunny: You'll get over there.
Sunny: Guys, please give, your boards, okay, to the candidate.
Sunny: So that we can decide the final, winner.
Sunny: So, one more minute, and after giving the board, guys, you can even write in the chat that I have done. You can mention done, okay, in the chat itself, so that I will get to know.
Sunny: Okay, so I can share my screen and I can show you the result, guys, just a second.
Sunny: Let me share my screen, wait.
Sunny: I hope it is visible. You can see Bala, Jyoti, Mandeep, Sumit, Bhargav, Gaurav.
Sunny: The Deepthi Anil is there, Kaushik is there, Ikhwag is there.
Sunny: And Smith is there, Mittal is there, Santosh, Piyush, Mayank, Naveen.
Sunny: And, according to the boards, I can see… Jyoti is having around 12%.
Sunny: And, Gaurav is having around 10%.
Sunny: And then Anil is having around 47%.
Sunny: And even Smith is having around 10%.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, Jyoti is, 12%.
Sunny: She's the second winner, and Anil is the first one.
Sunny: Now, there is a tie between Gauravinda and Smith.
Sunny: Gaurav and Smith, okay?
Sunny: Yeah, that's great. So guys, let me announce the final winner.
Sunny: Just a second.
Sunny: So there is, in total, 16 people, right?
Sunny: I think Yash has also given the demonstration, but it was not,
Sunny: Working well in their inner system, right here, Shukla.
Sunny: So, Wala, Jyoti, Mandeep, Sumit, then Gaurav was there.
Sunny: Sri Bharga was there, Gaurav was there, Deepti was there, Anil, K
Sunny: Ackwalk, Smith, Mithul, then Santos, Mayank, Pews, and Renjan, right?
Sunny: And even Naveen was there. Naveen and Behbab also was there. So let me write their name.
Sunny: Naveen… And then, wherever was there.
Sunny: So guys, here you can see… Jyothi is 12%.
Sunny: Gaurav is 10%, Anil is 46%, Smith is, again, 10%. Okay.
Sunny: So let me write the winner's name over here.
Sunny: Jyothi is the second winner.
Sunny: Second winner, then, we have Gaurav.
Sunny: He secured the 3rd position, 3rd winner.
Sunny: Then we have a Smith. He also secured the third position.
Sunny: Third position.
Sunny: Then until he's secured the first position.
Sunny: Okay, great, guys, so…
Sunny: Please give your mail ID, so, actually, I have your mail ID, you submitted via Google Form.
Sunny: We'll provide you the access of the upcoming, batch, okay?
Sunny: So, let me show you, the website.
Sunny: This is the website, guys.
Sunny: Krishnayak, right? So here you will go inside the live class, no?
Sunny: Instead of the live class, basically, we'll find out the live bleachers. So, this is the upcoming batch, which is going to be start from the
Sunny: Next Sunday onwards, so we'll provide you the access of the… we'll provide you the access of this batch, okay? So we'll provide you the access to Jyoti.
Sunny: Gotto.
Sunny: Anil and Smith.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so you will get the access of this badge.
Sunny: 4 candidates will get access, because, the two…
Sunny: people are having the same, vote percentage, as I can see.
Sunny: We're advanced.
piyush sahyu: So, actually, can I get a link of this meet? Actually, Gaurav was out for some reason, but he want to join again.
Sunny: No worries, I'll contact with him, okay? I'll, basically call… give call to him, okay? Don't worry.
piyush sahyu: It'.
Sunny: Because I have a number and all everything.
Sunny: Okay, fine, guys. So, I think you loved this session. Now, let's conclude it. Thank you very much for joining this, demonstration session. So, guys, did you like it? Yes or no? Please let me know in the chat. If you like this demonstration session, and I think you learned so many things, you got, the different, different application.
Sunny: From the different, different people, and now you can make… you can do the practice on top of that. I'll provide you the code base from everyone's end, so that you can practice, okay? Fine, thank you, bye-bye, guys, take care. Again, we'll see you in the next class. There we'll resume our session from the data parsing itself.
Sunny: So, thank you, bye-bye, guys. Take care. I'll see you in the next class. Yeah. Good night, guys.